<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hints>
  <hint wiki="Albert_Einstein">Developed the theory of relativity; famously failed his university entrance exam on the first try</hint>
  <hint wiki="Marie_Curie">First person to win Nobel Prizes in two different sciences: Physics and Chemistry</hint>
  <hint wiki="Isaac_Newton">Famously inspired by a falling apple; invented calculus simultaneously with Leibniz</hint>
  <hint wiki="Charles_Darwin">Spent five years aboard HMS Beagle before proposing natural selection</hint>
  <hint wiki="Nikola_Tesla">Held over 300 patents and had a famous rivalry with Edison over AC vs DC power</hint>
  <hint wiki="Thomas_Edison">Held over 1,000 US patents and said genius is &apos;1% inspiration, 99% perspiration&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Stephen_Hawking">Communicated via a speech synthesiser after losing his voice; wrote A Brief History of Time</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ada_Lovelace">Wrote the world&apos;s first algorithm, designed for a machine that hadn&apos;t been built yet</hint>
  <hint wiki="Napoleon">Was notably NOT short by the standards of his era; 5&apos;7&quot; was average height</hint>
  <hint wiki="Cleopatra">Spoke nine languages and was the first Ptolemaic ruler to actually learn Egyptian</hint>
  <hint wiki="Julius_Caesar">Reportedly cried &apos;Et tu, Brute?&apos; upon seeing his trusted friend among his assassins</hint>
  <hint wiki="Genghis_Khan">United warring Mongol tribes and created the largest contiguous land empire in history</hint>
  <hint wiki="Joan_of_Arc">Led French armies to key victories at age 17 before being burned at the stake at 19</hint>
  <hint wiki="Leonardo_da_Vinci">Filled over 13,000 pages of notebooks with ideas ranging from flying machines to anatomy</hint>
  <hint wiki="Michelangelo">Painted the Sistine Chapel ceiling lying on his back over four years, finishing in 1512</hint>
  <hint wiki="William_Shakespeare">Invented over 1,700 words still used in English, including &apos;bedroom&apos; and &apos;lonely&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pablo_Picasso">Co-founded Cubism and was so prolific he produced an estimated 20,000 works</hint>
  <hint wiki="Vincent_van_Gogh">Sold only one painting in his lifetime, famously cut off his own ear, and his work now fetches hundreds of millions</hint>
  <hint wiki="Frida_Kahlo">Painted 55 self-portraits, many depicting pain from a near-fatal bus accident at 18</hint>
  <hint wiki="Edgar_Allan_Poe">Married his 13-year-old cousin and died mysteriously at 40, found delirious in someone else&apos;s clothes</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mark_Twain">Born and died in years when Halley&apos;s Comet appeared; predicted his own death accordingly</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jane_Austen">Published her novels anonymously as &apos;By a Lady&apos;; never married despite writing about it endlessly</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ernest_Hemingway">Survived two plane crashes in two days, then read his own obituaries over breakfast</hint>
  <hint wiki="Abraham_Lincoln">The tallest US president at 6&apos;4&quot;; also a licensed bartender and skilled wrestler</hint>
  <hint wiki="Winston_Churchill">Delivered the &apos;We shall fight on the beaches&apos; speech and won the Nobel Prize in Literature</hint>
  <hint wiki="Nelson_Mandela">Served 27 years in prison before becoming South Africa&apos;s first democratically elected president</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mahatma_Gandhi">Led a 240-mile march to the sea to protest the British salt tax in 1930</hint>
  <hint wiki="George_Washington">Refused a salary as president and declined a third term, setting the two-term tradition</hint>
  <hint wiki="Queen_Victoria">Reigned for 63 years and had nine children who married into royal families across Europe</hint>
  <hint wiki="Franklin_D._Roosevelt">Only US president elected four times; led the nation through both the Depression and WWII</hint>
  <hint wiki="Muhammad_Ali">Refused military draft saying &apos;No Viet Cong ever called me n*****&apos;; stripped of his title</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pelé">Only player to win three FIFA World Cups and scored a record 1,281 goals in his career</hint>
  <hint wiki="Serena_Williams">Won the 2017 Australian Open while eight weeks pregnant, her 23rd Grand Slam title</hint>
  <hint wiki="Michael_Jordan">His Nike shoe deal launched one of the most iconic and lucrative sportswear brands in history</hint>
  <hint wiki="Usain_Bolt">Set the 100m world record of 9.58 seconds with a shoelace untied at Berlin 2009</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jesse_Owens">Won four gold medals at the 1936 Berlin Olympics under Hitler&apos;s gaze</hint>
  <hint wiki="Babe_Ruth">Hit 714 home runs and also pitched so well the Yankees didn&apos;t want to waste him on the mound</hint>
  <hint wiki="Elvis_Presley">His hip-swivelling TV appearances were considered too scandalous to film below the waist</hint>
  <hint wiki="Marilyn_Monroe">Sang &apos;Happy Birthday, Mr. President&apos; to JFK in a skin-tight dress at Madison Square Garden</hint>
  <hint wiki="Charlie_Chaplin">Was once rejected in his own lookalike contest; he entered for a joke</hint>
  <hint wiki="Frank_Sinatra">Known as &apos;Ol&apos; Blue Eyes&apos;; his FBI file ran to 1,275 pages</hint>
  <hint wiki="Freddie_Mercury">Wrote &apos;Bohemian Rhapsody&apos; in one sitting; the band nearly ditched it as too long</hint>
  <hint wiki="David_Bowie">Created at least 10 distinct alter egos, starting with Ziggy Stardust in 1972</hint>
  <hint wiki="Audrey_Hepburn">Spent her later years as a UNICEF Goodwill Ambassador, traveling to conflict zones across Africa, South America, and Asia to advocate for children</hint>
  <hint wiki="Alfred_Hitchcock">Made a cameo appearance in almost every one of his 50+ films</hint>
  <hint wiki="Walt_Disney">Was fired from a newspaper for &apos;lacking imagination&apos;; went on to build the world&apos;s most famous entertainment empire</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sigmund_Freud">Smoked 20 cigars a day and reportedly said &apos;Sometimes a cigar is just a cigar&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Karl_Marx">Spent most of his life broke and in exile, repeatedly writing to his closest collaborator to beg for money</hint>
  <hint wiki="Coco_Chanel">Liberated women from corsets and made the little black dress a wardrobe staple</hint>
  <hint wiki="Amelia_Earhart">First woman to fly solo across the Atlantic; disappeared attempting a round-the-world flight in 1937</hint>
  <hint wiki="Galileo_Galilei">Was placed under house arrest for the rest of his life for supporting a heliocentric solar system</hint>
  <hint wiki="Alan_Turing">Cracked the Nazi Enigma code, credited with shortening WWII by two years</hint>
  <hint wiki="Richard_Feynman">Decoded the Challenger disaster cause by dipping an O-ring in ice water at the live hearing</hint>
  <hint wiki="Carl_Sagan">Wrote the message on the Voyager Golden Record and coined the phrase &apos;billions and billions&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Louis_Pasteur">Invented pasteurisation and created the first vaccines for rabies and anthrax</hint>
  <hint wiki="Alexander_Fleming">Discovered penicillin by accident when mould contaminated a petri dish he&apos;d left before holiday</hint>
  <hint wiki="Rosalind_Franklin">Her Photo 51 X-ray image was the key evidence that revealed DNA&apos;s double-helix structure</hint>
  <hint wiki="Gregor_Mendel">Grew and counted over 10,000 pea plants in a monastery garden to discover heredity</hint>
  <hint wiki="Edwin_Hubble">Proved the universe is expanding; the space telescope launched in 1990 bears his name</hint>
  <hint wiki="Niels_Bohr">His model of the atom, electrons orbiting a nucleus like planets around the sun, became the iconic image of the atomic age</hint>
  <hint wiki="Archimedes">Allegedly ran naked through Syracuse shouting &apos;Eureka!&apos; after discovering water displacement in his bath</hint>
  <hint wiki="Nicolaus_Copernicus">A Catholic canon who quietly spent decades proving the Church&apos;s own cosmological teachings wrong</hint>
  <hint wiki="James_Watt">The unit of power is named after him: your phone charger, your lightbulb, your microwave are all rated in his name</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lise_Meitner">Co-discovered nuclear fission but was excluded from the Nobel Prize given to her male colleague</hint>
  <hint wiki="Max_Planck">Founded quantum theory but spent years trying to disprove it; the fundamental unit of quantum action is named after him</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ernest_Rutherford">Discovered the atomic nucleus by firing particles at gold foil and watching some bounce back</hint>
  <hint wiki="Michael_Faraday">Had almost no formal education and couldn&apos;t do higher mathematics; invented the electric motor anyway</hint>
  <hint wiki="Neil_Armstrong">Flubbed his planned &apos;one small step&apos; line slightly, but billions heard it as written anyway</hint>
  <hint wiki="Werner_Heisenberg">Gave his name to the Uncertainty Principle, stating you can&apos;t know both position and speed of a particle</hint>
  <hint wiki="James_Clerk_Maxwell">United electricity, magnetism, and light into four equations that Einstein called the greatest achievement in physics</hint>
  <hint wiki="Alexander_the_Great">Was never defeated in battle and had conquered most of the known world by age 30</hint>
  <hint wiki="Attila">Called &apos;The Scourge of God&apos;; turned back from sacking Rome partly due to a meeting with Pope Leo I</hint>
  <hint wiki="Marco_Polo">Spent 17 years at the court of Kublai Khan, dictated his travels while in prison, and has a popular swimming pool game named after him</hint>
  <hint wiki="Christopher_Columbus">Died still believing he had reached Asia; never knew he had landed in the Americas</hint>
  <hint wiki="Catherine_the_Great">Ruled Russia for 34 years, expanded its territory massively, and corresponded regularly with Voltaire</hint>
  <hint wiki="Elizabeth_I">The &apos;Virgin Queen&apos; who defeated the Spanish Armada in 1588 and never married</hint>
  <hint wiki="Elizabeth_II">Longest-reigning British monarch at 70 years, and the first female member of the royal family to serve in the military</hint>
  <hint wiki="Martin_Luther">Nailed 95 theses to a church door in 1517, sparking the Protestant schism that permanently divided Western Christianity</hint>
  <hint wiki="Che_Guevara">His iconic beret photo became the most reproduced image in history; he was executed in Bolivia aged 39</hint>
  <hint wiki="Margaret_Thatcher">The &apos;Iron Lady&apos; was Britain&apos;s first female prime minister and served three consecutive terms</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_F._Kennedy">The youngest elected US president; delivered the &apos;Ich bin ein Berliner&apos; speech in divided Berlin</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mao_Zedong">Founded the People&apos;s Republic of China in 1949 and initiated the Great Leap Forward</hint>
  <hint wiki="Joseph_Stalin">Born with a different name, he adopted a pseudonym meaning &apos;Man of Steel&apos;, and ruled the Soviet Union through it&apos;s most brutal regime</hint>
  <hint wiki="Thomas_Jefferson">Wrote the Declaration of Independence at 33; also invented the swivel chair and macaroni machine</hint>
  <hint wiki="Theodore_Roosevelt">Shot during a campaign speech, then spoke for 90 minutes before seeking medical treatment</hint>
  <hint wiki="Vladimir_Lenin">His embalmed body has been on public display in Moscow&apos;s Red Square since 1924</hint>
  <hint wiki="Fidel_Castro">Survived an estimated 638 assassination attempts, many organised by the CIA</hint>
  <hint wiki="Simón_Bolívar">Known as &apos;El Libertador&apos;; freed six South American countries from Spanish rule</hint>
  <hint wiki="Martin_Luther_King_Jr.">Delivered the &apos;I Have a Dream&apos; speech to 250,000 people in Washington DC in 1963</hint>
  <hint wiki="Harriet_Tubman">Led over 70 enslaved people to freedom via the Underground Railroad and never lost a passenger</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_Lennon">Wrote &apos;Imagine&apos; and was once more famous than Jesus, per his own controversial claim</hint>
  <hint wiki="Paul_McCartney">&apos;Yesterday&apos; is the most covered song in history; he has held the world record for most #1 albums</hint>
  <hint wiki="Michael_Jackson">Thriller is the best-selling album of all time; he moonwalked into history in 1983</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bob_Dylan">First rock musician to win the Nobel Prize in Literature; his acceptance speech was delivered by Patti Smith</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jimi_Hendrix">Self-taught, played guitar left-handed on a right-handed instrument strung upside-down</hint>
  <hint wiki="Whitney_Houston">Her version of &apos;I Will Always Love You&apos; is among the best-selling singles ever recorded</hint>
  <hint wiki="Madonna_(entertainer)">Has sold over 300 million records, making her the best-selling female recording artist of all time</hint>
  <hint wiki="Aretha_Franklin">The &apos;Queen of Soul&apos;; first woman inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bob_Marley">Reggae&apos;s global ambassador; his album Legend is the best-selling reggae album ever made</hint>
  <hint wiki="Louis_Armstrong">Known as &apos;Satchmo&apos;; his gravelly voice on &apos;What a Wonderful World&apos; became one of the most beloved recordings</hint>
  <hint wiki="Miles_Davis">His 1959 album Kind of Blue is the best-selling jazz record in history</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jim_Morrison">Front man of The Doors; earned the nickname &apos;The Lizard King&apos; and died in Paris aged 27</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kurt_Cobain">Wrote &apos;Smells Like Teen Spirit&apos; in 15 minutes and accidentally launched the grunge movement</hint>
  <hint wiki="Elton_John">Born plain Reginald Dwight, he reinvented himself as one of music&apos;s most flamboyant performers, famous for his outrageous costumes and enormous glasses collection</hint>
  <hint wiki="Prince_(musician)">Fought his record label by writing &apos;SLAVE&apos; on his face and changing his name to an unpronounceable symbol</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tina_Turner">The &apos;Queen of Rock and Roll&apos;; made her biggest comeback at age 44 with Private Dancer</hint>
  <hint wiki="Stevie_Wonder">Blind since shortly after birth, he became a UN Messenger of Peace and a driving force behind making Martin Luther King Jr. Day a US federal holiday</hint>
  <hint wiki="Marlon_Brando">Famously improvised the cat-stroking opening scene of The Godfather on the day of filming</hint>
  <hint wiki="James_Dean">Appeared in only three major films before dying in a car crash at 24; became an eternal rebel icon</hint>
  <hint wiki="Humphrey_Bogart">&apos;Here&apos;s looking at you, kid&apos;, voted the greatest male star in Hollywood history by the AFI</hint>
  <hint wiki="Grace_Kelly">Gave up Hollywood stardom to marry Prince Rainier III and become Princess of Monaco</hint>
  <hint wiki="Cary_Grant">His debonair screen persona was invented from scratch; born Archibald Leach in a Bristol working-class family</hint>
  <hint wiki="Orson_Welles">Directed and starred in Citizen Kane at 25; his War of the Worlds radio broadcast caused public panic in 1938</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ingrid_Bergman">Her affair with an Italian director caused such a scandal that she was denounced on the US Senate floor and effectively blacklisted from Hollywood for years</hint>
  <hint wiki="Clark_Gable">Known as &apos;The King of Hollywood&apos;; his refusal to wear an undershirt in It Happened One Night supposedly crashed undershirt sales</hint>
  <hint wiki="Charles_Dickens">He based the miserly Ebenezer Scrooge partly on real London slum conditions he witnessed as a child laborer in a boot-blacking factory.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Leo_Tolstoy">He wrote one of the longest novels ever published; War and Peace spans over 1,200 pages and tracks five aristocratic families through Napoleon&apos;s invasion of Russia.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Fyodor_Dostoevsky">He was lined up before a firing squad and pardoned at the last second, an experience that permanently shaped his obsessive exploration of death and suffering in his novels.</hint>
  <hint wiki="George_Orwell">He fought in the Spanish Civil War and was shot through the throat by a sniper, surviving to write two of the most influential political novels of the 20th century.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Franz_Kafka">He asked his friend Max Brod to burn all his manuscripts after his death; Brod ignored the request, giving the world The Trial and The Metamorphosis.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Virginia_Woolf">She helped pioneer the stream-of-consciousness technique in novels like Mrs Dalloway, and co-founded the Hogarth Press from her living room.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Oscar_Wilde">He was sentenced to two years of hard labor for gross indecency and wrote his most heartbreaking work, The Ballad of Reading Gaol, from prison.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Arthur_Conan_Doyle">He tried to kill off Sherlock Holmes at Reichenbach Falls in 1893, but public outcry was so fierce he was forced to bring the detective back from the dead.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Agatha_Christie">The best-selling mystery writer of all time; her whodunit play The Mousetrap has run continuously in London&apos;s West End since 1952</hint>
  <hint wiki="J._R._R._Tolkien">He invented entire languages, including Quenya and Sindarin, before writing the stories of Middle-earth to give those languages a world to live in.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Victor_Hugo">He was exiled from France for opposing Napoleon III and wrote Les Misérables from the island of Guernsey, becoming a hero to the French working class.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Alexandre_Dumas">He wrote The Count of Monte Cristo and The Three Musketeers so prolifically that he was rumored to run a fiction factory with ghostwriters, which he enthusiastically denied.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Rembrandt">He painted over 80 self-portraits across his lifetime, more than almost any artist in history, creating an unparalleled visual autobiography of aging and hardship.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Salvador_Dalí">He painted The Persistence of Memory, the melting clocks, in under two hours, reportedly inspired by staring at a piece of melting Camembert cheese.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Plato">He was originally a wrestler who competed at the Isthmian Games, and his philosophical dialogues, featuring his teacher Socrates, still anchor university philosophy courses worldwide.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Aristotle">He tutored a teenage Alexander the Great for three years and wrote foundational texts on logic, biology, ethics, and drama that shaped Western thought for two millennia.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Voltaire">He was imprisoned in the Bastille twice and exiled from France, yet kept writing sharp satirical attacks on the Church and absolute monarchy from across the border.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Friedrich_Nietzsche">He declared God is dead not as a boast but as a warning, and spent his final decade in a state of mental collapse, cared for by his mother.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Immanuel_Kant">Proposed that moral actions must pass a single test: could you will everyone to act the same way? He called this the categorical imperative</hint>
  <hint wiki="René_Descartes">He wrote &apos;I think, therefore I am&apos; while literally hiding in a warm stove room during winter, which he said was where his best ideas came from.</hint>
  <hint wiki="LeBron_James">He went straight from high school to the NBA and was on the cover of Sports Illustrated at 17, then delivered Cleveland its first major sports championship in 52 years in 2016.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tiger_Woods">He won the 1997 Masters by 12 strokes, the largest margin in tournament history, at age 21, and went on to hold the world number one ranking for a record 683 weeks.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Roger_Federer">He won 20 Grand Slam singles titles and was known for a playing style so fluid that opponents and fans often described watching him as closer to art than sport.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Cristiano_Ronaldo">He is the all-time top scorer in international men&apos;s football and the first player to score at five different FIFA World Cups.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lionel_Messi">He was diagnosed with a growth hormone deficiency as a child; Barcelona paid for his treatment at age 13 on the condition he moved from Argentina to join their academy.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Diego_Maradona">In a single 1986 World Cup quarter-final against England, he scored both the infamous Hand of God goal and what FIFA voted the Goal of the Century: in the same match.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ayrton_Senna">He qualified on pole position 65 times in Formula 1, a record that stood for 16 years, and famously described entering a trance-like state while lapping Monaco in the wet.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Michael_Schumacher">He won seven Formula 1 World Championships, five of them consecutively, and still holds the record for most wins in a single season.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jackie_Robinson">When he took the field in 1947, he became the first Black player in MLB&apos;s modern era; his jersey number, #42, is the only number retired across every team in baseball</hint>
  <hint wiki="Wayne_Gretzky">He scored so many points in his NHL career that if you removed all his goals, his assists alone would still make him the all-time leading scorer in league history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mike_Tyson">He became the youngest heavyweight boxing world champion in history at age 20, and was known for a ferocious style that ended fights in the opening rounds.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Steffi_Graf">She is the only tennis player, male or female, to win the Golden Slam: all four Grand Slams plus the Olympic gold medal in the same calendar year (1988).</hint>
  <hint wiki="Martina_Navratilova">She won 9 Wimbledon singles titles and was the world number one for a total of 332 weeks, often credited with transforming women&apos;s tennis into a power game.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jane_Goodall">She arrived in Tanzania in 1960 with no formal degree and discovered that chimpanzees make and use tools, overturning the scientific definition of what makes humans unique.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Neil_deGrasse_Tyson">He successfully campaigned for Pluto&apos;s reclassification as a dwarf planet in 2006, earning him both scientific acclaim and years of angry letters from Pluto fans.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bill_Nye">His Saturday morning TV show made him the science teacher for an entire generation of 1990s kids, and he later became a prominent public voice on climate change.</hint>
  <hint wiki="David_Attenborough">Has been narrating natural history documentaries for over seven decades: his career spans from black-and-white BBC broadcasts in the 1950s to 4K streaming today</hint>
  <hint wiki="Buzz_Aldrin">He was the second human to walk on the Moon, and while still on the lunar surface, he privately took Communion, a fact NASA kept quiet for years.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Yuri_Gagarin">On April 12, 1961, he orbited Earth in 108 minutes aboard Vostok 1, becoming the first human in space, and was reportedly so calm during launch he whistled a folk song.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sally_Ride">She became the first American woman in space in 1983, and after her death it was revealed she had been in a same-sex relationship for 27 years.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Florence_Nightingale">She used statistical charts, including an early form of the pie chart, to convince the British government that more soldiers were dying from preventable infection than from wounds.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Wright_brothers">Orville and Wilbur&apos;s first powered flight at Kitty Hawk in 1903 lasted just 12 seconds, but they were so secretive about their work that the press largely ignored it for years.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Alexander_Graham_Bell">He invented the telephone but reportedly found it so intrusive he refused to have one in his own study, preferring uninterrupted work.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Henry_Ford">He didn&apos;t invent the automobile, but he introduced the moving assembly line and paid his workers $5 a day, double the going rate, so they could afford to buy the cars they built.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pythagoras">He led a secretive religious cult in ancient Greece that banned followers from eating beans and believed that numbers held mystical cosmic power.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Euclid">His geometry textbook Elements was used in schools for over 2,000 years and is considered the most successful textbook ever written.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Erwin_Schrödinger">He devised the famous thought experiment of a cat that is simultaneously alive and dead to mock what he saw as the absurdity of Copenhagen quantum mechanics.</hint>
  <hint wiki="J._Robert_Oppenheimer">He directed the Manhattan Project; watching the first atomic test, he later recalled a line from the Bhagavad Gita: &apos;Now I am become Death, the destroyer of worlds.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Enrico_Fermi">He built the world&apos;s first nuclear reactor in a squash court under a university stadium in 1942, and posed the paradox that asks why, given the vastness of the universe, we have never heard from alien civilisations</hint>
  <hint wiki="Marie_Antoinette">Queen of France who was guillotined at 37 during the Revolution, forever linked to the phrase &apos;let them eat cake&apos;, which historians say she almost certainly never said</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hippocrates">He is credited with separating medicine from superstition and divine punishment, insisting illness had natural causes, and his name still echoes in the oath doctors take today.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Grace_Hopper">She invented the first compiler and popularized the term &apos;debugging&apos; after literally finding a moth in a computer relay; the world&apos;s largest gathering of women in tech is named after her</hint>
  <hint wiki="Wernher_von_Braun">He designed the V-2 rocket for Nazi Germany, the world&apos;s first ballistic missile, then surrendered to the Americans and led the team that built the Saturn V rocket that took humans to the Moon.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Steve_Jobs">He was famously ousted from Apple in 1985, spent a decade building Pixar and NeXT, then returned to rescue a nearly bankrupt Apple and turned it into the most valuable company on Earth.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bill_Gates">He dropped out of Harvard and co-founded Microsoft at 19, and his ruthless licensing deal for MS-DOS with IBM is often credited as the single move that made him a billionaire.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Elon_Musk">Paid $44 billion for Twitter, renamed it X, and triggered a mass advertiser exodus; also tweeted &apos;funding secured&apos; about a Tesla buyout that never happened, leading to an SEC investigation</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mark_Zuckerberg">He launched Facebook from his Harvard dorm room in 2004 and by his late 20s had built a platform used by more than a billion people, and faced congressional testimony over its impact on democracy.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jeff_Bezos">He started Amazon by packing books in his garage and later built a company so dominant it reshaped global retail, logistics, and cloud computing, and funded his own trip to space.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Larry_Page">He and Sergey Brin developed the PageRank algorithm as a Stanford PhD project, rating web pages by how many other pages link to them, turning it into the foundation of Google.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sergey_Brin">He co-founded Google with Larry Page in a Stanford dorm, and the name came from a misspelling of &apos;googol&apos;: the number 1 followed by 100 zeros.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Steve_Wozniak">He single-handedly designed the Apple I and Apple II computers from scratch, and was so generous he sold his HP calculator to fund the first production run of the Apple I.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sundar_Pichai">He rose from a middle-class family in Chennai, where his household had no car and he slept in the living room, to become CEO of Google and its parent company Alphabet.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tim_Cook">He took over Apple after Steve Jobs&apos;s death in 2011 and made it the first public company to reach a $1 trillion market valuation, steering it through the smartphone era&apos;s peak.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sam_Altman">He led OpenAI through the release of ChatGPT, the fastest-growing consumer application in history, and was dramatically fired and rehired by the board within five days in 2023.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jensen_Huang">He co-founded Nvidia in 1993 and bet the company on graphics chips for gaming; decades later, those same chips became the essential hardware for training artificial intelligence.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Warren_Buffett">He bought his first stock at age 11 and has donated the vast majority of his multi-hundred-billion-dollar fortune to charity: mostly to the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Oprah_Winfrey">She grew up in poverty in rural Mississippi and became the first Black female billionaire in history, with her book club recommendations alone capable of making novels instant bestsellers.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Martha_Stewart">She built a lifestyle empire worth hundreds of millions of dollars and served five months in federal prison for insider trading, then returned to television and rebuilt her brand.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Richard_Branson">He launched Virgin Records, Virgin Atlantic, and Virgin Galactic, and set multiple world records in hot-air balloon and powerboat journeys across the Atlantic and Pacific.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Donald_Trump">He was a New York real estate developer and reality TV host who became the 45th President, then the first former US president to be convicted of felony crimes.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Howard_Hughes">He was a record-breaking aviator, Hollywood producer, and one of the wealthiest people alive, before retreating into extreme reclusion and severe OCD in his later decades.</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_D._Rockefeller">He built Standard Oil into a monopoly controlling 90% of US oil refining, was forced to break it up by the Supreme Court in 1911, and the successor companies still rank among the world&apos;s largest.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Andrew_Carnegie">He sold his steel empire for nearly $500 million in 1901 and then gave almost all of it away, funding over 2,500 public libraries across the English-speaking world.</hint>
  <hint wiki="J._P._Morgan">He personally organized a private bailout of the US government during the 1893 financial crisis and again stopped a banking collapse in 1907: effectively acting as a one-man central bank.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Estée_Lauder_(businesswoman)">She built her cosmetics empire from scratch by insisting on giving away free samples, a then-radical idea, and turned a kitchen recipe into one of the world&apos;s most valuable beauty companies.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Barack_Obama">He became the first African American President of the United States in 2009 and was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in the first year of his presidency.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Michelle_Obama">Her Let&apos;s Move! campaign to combat childhood obesity and her memoir Becoming, which sold over 17 million copies, made her one of the most admired public figures in the world.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Joe_Biden">He was first elected to the US Senate at 29, too young to be seated, and decades later became the oldest person ever inaugurated as President at age 78.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kamala_Harris">She became the first woman, first Black American, and first person of South Asian descent to serve as Vice President of the United States.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hillary_Clinton">She was the first woman nominated for president by a major US political party, served as Secretary of State, and won the 2016 popular vote while losing the Electoral College.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bill_Clinton">He survived an impeachment trial over the Monica Lewinsky affair and left office with the highest end-of-term approval rating of any US president since World War II.</hint>
  <hint wiki="George_W._Bush">He launched the invasion of Afghanistan and Iraq following the September 11 attacks, reshaping US foreign policy and the Middle East for decades.</hint>
  <hint wiki="George_H._W._Bush">He led a 35-nation coalition to expel Iraq from Kuwait in the Gulf War but famously broke his &apos;read my lips: no new taxes&apos; pledge, costing him a second term.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ronald_Reagan">A former Hollywood actor, he became the 40th President and is credited, controversially, with accelerating the end of the Cold War through military spending and direct diplomacy with Gorbachev.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jimmy_Carter">A peanut farmer from Georgia who became President, and after losing re-election went on to become arguably the most productive ex-president in US history, building houses with Habitat for Humanity into his 90s</hint>
  <hint wiki="Richard_Nixon">The only US President to resign from office, stepping down in 1974 over the Watergate break-in and cover-up; he had also opened diplomatic relations with China</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lyndon_B._Johnson">He signed the Civil Rights Act and Voting Rights Act into law, transforming American society; his escalation of the Vietnam War consumed his presidency and led him to decline re-election</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dwight_D._Eisenhower">He commanded the Allied forces on D-Day during World War II, then as President launched the Interstate Highway System and warned of the growing &apos;military-industrial complex.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Harry_S._Truman">He made the decision to drop atomic bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki to end World War II, a call that remains one of the most debated in modern history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Andrew_Jackson">He survived two assassination attempts and was famous for his violent temper: he dueled over 100 times and carried a bullet in his chest for the rest of his life.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ulysses_S._Grant">He accepted Robert E. Lee&apos;s surrender to end the Civil War and, facing bankruptcy from a financial fraud near the end of his life, finished his acclaimed memoirs just days before his death.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Benjamin_Franklin">He flew a kite in a thunderstorm to prove lightning was electricity, invented bifocals and the lightning rod, and negotiated the alliance with France that won the American Revolution.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Alexander_Hamilton">He was orphaned as a teenager in the Caribbean and talked his way to America, became George Washington&apos;s right-hand man, and founded the US financial system: before dying in a duel with the sitting Vice President.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bernie_Sanders">Ran two strong campaigns for the Democratic presidential nomination, winning millions of votes on a platform of wealth inequality and universal healthcare he had championed in Congress for decades</hint>
  <hint wiki="Nancy_Pelosi">She became the first woman elected Speaker of the House and famously tore up a copy of Donald Trump&apos;s State of the Union address on national television behind his back.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Alexandria_Ocasio-Cortez">She was working as a bartender in New York when she ran for Congress in 2018 and, at 29, became the youngest woman ever elected to the US House of Representatives.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mitch_McConnell">He blocked President Obama&apos;s Supreme Court nominee Merrick Garland from receiving a hearing for nearly a year, then filled three Supreme Court seats during the Trump administration.</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_McCain">He was a prisoner of war in Hanoi for over five years, refused early release to avoid giving propaganda value to his captors, and decades later became a Senate maverick known for bipartisan deals.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mitt_Romney">He made a fortune in private equity, rescued the 2002 Salt Lake City Olympics from a corruption scandal, and later became the first sitting senator to vote to convict a president of his own party.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Al_Gore">He won the popular vote in the 2000 presidential election but lost the presidency when the Supreme Court halted a Florida recount, then won the Nobel Peace Prize for his climate advocacy.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dick_Cheney">He was widely considered the most powerful Vice President in US history, a key architect of the Iraq War, and famously shot a friend in the face on a quail hunting trip.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ruth_Bader_Ginsburg">She was one of only nine women in her Harvard Law class in 1956 and spent her career dismantling gender discrimination laws, becoming a pop-culture icon known simply as &apos;the Notorious RBG.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Antonin_Scalia">He championed originalism, interpreting the Constitution strictly as written, and formed an unlikely but genuine friendship with his ideological opposite, Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sonia_Sotomayor">She grew up in a Bronx housing project and was diagnosed with diabetes at age 8, going on to become the first Latina Supreme Court Justice in US history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sandra_Day_O&apos;Connor">She became the first woman on the US Supreme Court in 1981 after Ronald Reagan appointed her, often serving as the decisive swing vote on contentious cases for two decades.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Justin_Trudeau">He is the son of a former Prime Minister and became Canada&apos;s second-youngest PM, initially riding a wave of progressive optimism before facing a series of political scandals.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pierre_Trudeau">He was a flamboyant intellectual who pirouetted behind the Queen&apos;s back, dated Barbra Streisand, and invoked the War Measures Act against Québec separatist terrorists in 1970.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Boris_Johnson">He was the face of the successful Brexit campaign, became Prime Minister, and then resigned in disgrace after a series of scandals including parties held at Downing Street during COVID lockdowns.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tony_Blair">He won a landslide election in 1997 ending 18 years of Conservative rule, brokered the Good Friday Agreement in Northern Ireland, and then saw his legacy overshadowed by the invasion of Iraq.</hint>
  <hint wiki="David_Cameron">He called the 2016 Brexit referendum expecting to win it and settle the issue, then resigned within hours of losing, leaving Britain in a political crisis that lasted nearly a decade.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Rishi_Sunak">He became Britain&apos;s first Prime Minister of Indian heritage and its youngest in over 200 years, then led the Conservative Party to its worst election defeat in nearly a century.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Keir_Starmer">He was a human rights lawyer who led the Crown Prosecution Service before entering politics, then won a landslide victory to become Prime Minister in 2024, ending 14 years of Conservative government.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Angela_Merkel">She was a quantum chemist from East Germany who became Chancellor for 16 years, making her the longest-serving leader of any major Western democracy of her era.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Emmanuel_Macron">He founded his own political movement from scratch and became France&apos;s youngest-ever President at 39, having previously been advised in part by his wife: his former high school drama teacher.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Vladimir_Putin">A former KGB intelligence officer, he has dominated Russian politics for over two decades and ordered the full-scale invasion of Ukraine in 2022, triggering Europe&apos;s largest land war since World War II.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Volodymyr_Zelenskyy">A former comedian and TV star, he refused evacuation after Russia&apos;s 2022 invasion with the now-iconic line: &apos;I need ammunition, not a ride.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Xi_Jinping">Oversaw the largest anti-corruption campaign in the Communist Party&apos;s history, investigating over a million officials, and presided over the period that lifted more people out of extreme poverty than any government in history</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kim_Jong_Un">He ordered the execution of his own uncle Jang Song-thaek in 2013 and later met with Donald Trump in three historic, and ultimately fruitless, summits.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kim_Jong_Il">He reportedly had a personal collection of over 20,000 films and kidnapped a South Korean filmmaker to build a North Korean movie industry.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Benjamin_Netanyahu">The longest-serving Prime Minister in Israel&apos;s history, he was re-elected while under indictment on corruption charges and oversaw the military campaign in Gaza that international courts have described as genocide</hint>
  <hint wiki="Narendra_Modi">He rose from selling tea as a child to leading India&apos;s 1.4 billion people, and his 2014 landslide win ended a decade of Congress rule by one of the largest democratic mandates in history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Shinzo_Abe">Japan&apos;s longest-serving prime minister, he was assassinated while giving a campaign speech in 2022: the first such killing of a major Japanese leader in modern times.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mikhail_Gorbachev">His policies of glasnost and perestroika inadvertently unravelled the Soviet Union, making him the last leader of a superpower that ceased to exist on his watch.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Boris_Yeltsin">He stood on a tank outside the Russian parliament in 1991 to defy a coup attempt, then on New Year&apos;s Eve 1999 unexpectedly resigned live on television, handing power to a little-known Vladimir Putin.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hugo_Chávez">He survived a coup attempt in 2002, then used Venezuela&apos;s oil wealth to fund a pan-Latin American socialist movement he called the Bolivarian Revolution.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Saddam_Hussein">He used chemical weapons on his own Kurdish citizens at Halabja in 1988, killing thousands, and was later found hiding in an underground hole before his execution in 2006.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Muammar_Gaddafi">He ruled Libya for 42 years with a blend of pan-African ideology and eccentric theatrics, including travelling with an all-female bodyguard unit and pitching a tent in foreign capitals.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Yasser_Arafat">He shared the Nobel Peace Prize in 1994 after signing the Oslo Accords, yet spent his final years under Israeli military siege in his Ramallah compound.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Anwar_Sadat">He flew to Jerusalem in 1977, a stunning act no Arab leader had attempted, and became the first Arab head of state to officially recognise Israel, earning a Nobel Peace Prize and later an assassin&apos;s bullet.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Leila_Khaled">The first woman to hijack an airplane, she became an iconic image of the Palestinian resistance movement: her keffiyeh-wrapped portrait one of the most reproduced political photographs of the 20th century</hint>
  <hint wiki="Indira_Gandhi">She declared a state of emergency in 1975, suspending democracy for nearly two years, then was assassinated in 1984 by her own Sikh bodyguards after ordering troops to storm the Golden Temple.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pope_Francis">The first Jesuit and first Latin American pope, he chose a name no pope had ever used, a deliberate nod to a life of simplicity, and famously asked &apos;Who am I to judge?&apos; about gay priests</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pope_John_Paul_II">He survived an assassination attempt in St. Peter&apos;s Square in 1981, later personally visiting and forgiving his attacker in prison, and his 1979 visit to Poland helped ignite the Solidarity movement that cracked communist rule.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pope_Benedict_XVI">The first pope to resign in nearly 600 years, he stepped down in 2013 citing failing strength, stunning a Church that had assumed the papacy was a lifetime office.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mother_Teresa">She founded the Missionaries of Charity in Calcutta&apos;s slums in 1950 and won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1979, refusing the traditional banquet and asking that its cost be donated to the poor instead.</hint>
  <hint wiki="14th_Dalai_Lama">Identified as the reincarnation of his predecessor at age two, he has led the Tibetan government-in-exile from Dharamsala, India since fleeing a Chinese crackdown in 1959.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Adolf_Hitler">A failed Austrian artist who rose to Chancellor of Germany in 1933, he orchestrated the systematic murder of six million Jews and plunged the world into a war that killed over 70 million people.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Benito_Mussolini">The inventor of modern fascism, he made the trains run on time, or so the myth went, and was killed by partisans in 1945, his body hung upside down at a Milan petrol station.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Osama_bin_Laden">The Saudi-born architect of the September 11, 2001 attacks, he evaded capture for nearly a decade before U.S. Navy SEALs killed him at a compound in Abbottabad, Pakistan in 2011.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Henry_Kissinger">Accused of orchestrating war crimes including the secret bombing of Cambodia, yet won the Nobel Peace Prize so controversially that two committee members resigned in protest</hint>
  <hint wiki="Colin_Powell">A four-star general who became the first Black U.S. Secretary of State, he later called his 2003 UN speech presenting the case for WMDs in Iraq a &apos;blot&apos; that would forever stain his record.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Condoleezza_Rice">The first Black woman to serve as U.S. Secretary of State, she was National Security Advisor on 9/11 and a concert-level classical pianist who once performed alongside cellist Yo-Yo Ma.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Madeleine_Albright">The first female U.S. Secretary of State, she famously communicated diplomatic messages through her brooch choices, a habit she called &apos;pin diplomacy&apos;, and had fled Czechoslovakia as a child refugee.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Charles_III">He waited longer than any heir in British history to ascend the throne, becoming king at 73, and had championed environmental causes and organic farming for decades before it was fashionable.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Diana,_Princess_of_Wales">Her 1997 funeral drew two billion television viewers worldwide, and her landmine-clearing campaign in Angola, broadcast globally just months before her death, helped accelerate an international ban on the weapons.</hint>
  <hint wiki="William,_Prince_of_Wales">He served as an RAF search-and-rescue helicopter pilot before royal duties took over, and his surprise 2010 proposal to Kate Middleton used his late mother Diana&apos;s sapphire engagement ring.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Prince_Harry,_Duke_of_Sussex">He served two combat tours in Afghanistan, making him the first British royal to see active front-line duty in 25 years, before later resigning as a senior royal and moving to California.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Meghan,_Duchess_of_Sussex">A mixed-race American actress best known for &apos;Suits,&apos; she became the first divorced, biracial American to marry into the modern British royal family, and the couple&apos;s 2021 Oprah interview sent shockwaves through the monarchy.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Catherine,_Princess_of_Wales">A commoner who met Prince William at St. Andrews University, she became the first future queen consort to earn a university degree, and her fashion choices routinely sell out within minutes.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Prince_Philip,_Duke_of_Edinburgh">He served in the Royal Navy during WWII and was present at Japan&apos;s formal surrender in Tokyo Bay, then spent 73 years as Queen Elizabeth II&apos;s consort: the longest-serving royal consort in British history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Eleanor_Roosevelt">She transformed the ceremonial role of First Lady into an activist platform, writing a daily newspaper column and becoming the first U.S. delegate to the UN, where she helped draft the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jacqueline_Kennedy_Onassis">She was seated beside her husband when he was shot dead in a Dallas motorcade in 1963; she later remarried a Greek shipping billionaire and quietly built a second career as a book editor in New York.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Malcolm_X">He rejected integration and demanded Black self-determination at a time when that was considered radical, building a mass movement around pride, economic independence, and armed self-defence; a pilgrimage to Mecca transformed his views in the final year of his life.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Rosa_Parks">Her refusal to give up her bus seat in Montgomery, Alabama in 1955 was not a spontaneous act of tiredness: she was a trained NAACP activist whose arrest had been carefully chosen to spark the boycott.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Frederick_Douglass">An escaped slave who taught himself to read in secret, he became the most photographed American of the 19th century and wrote one of the most searing autobiographies in the English language.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Susan_B._Anthony">She was arrested and fined $100 for voting in the 1872 presidential election, and died 14 years before the amendment bearing her name gave women the vote.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Malala_Yousafzai">Shot in the head by a Taliban gunman on her school bus in Pakistan&apos;s Swat Valley at age 15, she survived to become the youngest-ever Nobel Peace Prize laureate and continues to campaign for girls&apos; education.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Greta_Thunberg">She started her climate protest alone outside the Swedish parliament at age 15 with a hand-painted sign, and within two years had inspired millions of students worldwide to strike from school every Friday.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Anne_Frank">She kept a diary for two years while hiding with her family in a concealed Amsterdam apartment during the Nazi occupation; her father Otto was the only family member to survive the camps and published her words.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tom_Hanks">The only actor to win back-to-back Best Actor Oscars since Spencer Tracy, he achieved it for &apos;Philadelphia&apos; and &apos;Forrest Gump&apos; in 1994 and 1995.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tom_Cruise">He performed his own stunts, including clinging to the outside of a moving Airbus A400M at takeoff, and has been synonymous with the Mission: Impossible franchise for three decades.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Brad_Pitt">He spent years eating on screen in nearly every film as a deliberate character choice, and his production company Plan B brought &apos;The Departed,&apos; &apos;12 Years a Slave,&apos; and &apos;Moonlight&apos; to the Oscars.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Angelina_Jolie">She became a UN Goodwill Ambassador after filming &apos;Lara Croft&apos; in Cambodia, going on to make over 60 field visits to refugee camps worldwide and adopt three children from Cambodia, Ethiopia, and Vietnam.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Leonardo_DiCaprio">He was nominated for an Oscar five times before finally winning for &apos;The Revenant&apos; in 2016, during which he actually ate raw bison liver on camera despite being a vegetarian.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Robert_De_Niro">He gained 60 pounds to play the older Jake LaMotta in &apos;Raging Bull&apos; and actually trained as a boxer so convincingly that LaMotta said he could have gone professional.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Al_Pacino">His &apos;hoo-ah!&apos; in &apos;Scent of a Woman&apos; earned him his only Oscar after seven previous nominations, and he reportedly based his Scarface accent on a Cuban friend rather than research.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jack_Nicholson">A courtside fixture at LA Lakers games for decades, he discovered at age 37 that the woman he&apos;d grown up believing was his sister was actually his mother.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Robert_Redford">He co-founded the Sundance Film Festival in Utah, turning it into the world&apos;s premier showcase for independent cinema and single-handedly reshaping how non-studio films reach audiences.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Paul_Newman">He donated all profits from his Newman&apos;s Own food brand to charity, ultimately over $600 million, and was still competitive racing cars into his late seventies.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Clint_Eastwood">He served as mayor of Carmel-by-the-Sea, California in the 1980s, and directed &apos;Million Dollar Baby&apos; and &apos;Unforgiven&apos;, both Best Picture Oscar winners, decades into his career.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Harrison_Ford">He was working as a carpenter installing a door at a studio when George Lucas spotted him and cast him as Han Solo, launching one of Hollywood&apos;s most durable careers.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sean_Connery">He was voted &apos;Sexiest Man of the Century&apos; by People magazine at age 69, and reportedly learned his iconic rolled &apos;r&apos; from a speech therapist while preparing to play James Bond.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Anthony_Hopkins">He won the Oscar for Best Actor for &apos;The Silence of the Lambs&apos; with only about 16 minutes of screen time, one of the shortest performances ever to claim the award, and is also a published composer.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Morgan_Freeman">He didn&apos;t land his first major film role until his early fifties, and his narration is so distinctive that NASA used his voice to introduce the Deep Impact mission to the public.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Samuel_L._Jackson">A recovering addict who got sober at 40, he has since become the highest-grossing actor in box-office history and reportedly carries a favourite golf club on every film set.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Denzel_Washington">The first Black actor to win two Academy Awards, he turned down the role of Morpheus in &apos;The Matrix&apos; and has said his greatest performance is his stage work: particularly &apos;Fences,&apos; which he also directed.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Will_Smith">He walked on stage at the Oscars in 2022 and slapped presenter Chris Rock, then minutes later won Best Actor for &apos;King Richard&apos; in one of the most shocking moments in the ceremony&apos;s history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Eddie_Murphy">His 1983 stand-up special &apos;Delirious&apos; is considered one of the greatest in history, and at his peak in the mid-1980s he was the highest-paid entertainer in the world.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Robin_Williams">An improvisational genius who ad-libbed so relentlessly that the script for &apos;Aladdin&apos; was rewritten around his riffs, he was posthumously diagnosed with Lewy body dementia, a disease his widow called &apos;the terrorist in his brain.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jim_Carrey">He wrote himself a cheque for $10 million for &apos;acting services rendered&apos; when he was broke and struggling, dated it for Thanksgiving 1995, and &apos;Dumb and Dumber&apos; came out just before that date and made him exactly that.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Adam_Sandler">Notoriously passed over by mainstream awards, he threatened to make the worst movie ever if he didn&apos;t get an Oscar nomination for &apos;Uncut Gems&apos;, and his performance is still cited as one of the finest of that year.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bill_Murray">He is famously uncontactable, having no agent or manager, only a phone number that leads to a voicemail, which means directors must persist for months, lending his cameos an air of legend.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Steve_Martin">He pioneered the &apos;anti-comedian&apos; in the 1970s, filling arenas with absurdist non-jokes, then reinvented himself as a respected playwright, novelist, and bluegrass banjo player.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mike_Myers">He created the Austin Powers franchise on a $16 million budget that grossed over $312 million globally, and based Dr. Evil partly on his old Saturday Night Live producer Lorne Michaels.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ben_Stiller">He wrote and directed &apos;Zoolander&apos; as a short film for the 1996 VH1 Fashion Awards before it became a feature, and the blue steel look was lifted from an actual modelling pose he spotted in a magazine.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dustin_Hoffman">Famously method to a fault: he stayed awake for days to play an exhausted character in &apos;Marathon Man,&apos; prompting co-star Laurence Olivier&apos;s exasperated response: &apos;Have you tried acting, dear boy?&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sylvester_Stallone">He wrote the script for &apos;Rocky&apos; in three days and refused to sell it unless he could star in it, turning down offers of up to $350,000 to cast a bigger name, and the film won Best Picture.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Arnold_Schwarzenegger">He won the Mr. Olympia bodybuilding title seven times, then became a Hollywood action star, then served two terms as Governor of California, a trajectory no one else in history has matched.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bruce_Willis">He was a struggling bartender in New York when he landed &apos;Moonlighting&apos; over tens of thousands of auditionees, and &apos;Die Hard&apos;, initially considered a risky casting choice, redefined the action genre.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mel_Gibson">He was broke and sleeping in a friend&apos;s car when he auditioned for &apos;Mad Max&apos; in 1979 after being beaten up the night before: the bruises apparently convincing the director he was perfect for the role.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kevin_Costner">He financed the $175 million epic &apos;Waterworld&apos; himself when studios balked at the budget, and despite being a critical punching bag, the film eventually turned a profit on home video.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Michael_Douglas">He produced &apos;One Flew Over the Cuckoo&apos;s Nest&apos;, which swept all five major Oscars, before he was a household name as an actor, having inherited the rights from his father Kirk.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kirk_Douglas">He was one of the few Hollywood stars to publicly break the McCarthy-era blacklist by crediting screenwriter Dalton Trumbo, a communist list member, on &apos;Spartacus&apos; in 1960.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Gene_Hackman">His detective in &apos;The French Connection&apos; improvised the now-classic line &apos;Have you ever picked your feet in Poughkeepsie?&apos; mid-interrogation, and the suspect&apos;s confused reaction was real.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Christopher_Walken">He re-punctuates every script he receives by removing all the commas, creating his own rhythm, a technique he says makes dialogue feel more spontaneous, and was once a lion tamer.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Johnny_Depp">He based his Jack Sparrow performance on Keith Richards of the Rolling Stones and a rubber-legged cartoon character, delivering the walk to Disney executives who feared they&apos;d hired a drunk.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Keanu_Reeves">He gave away roughly $80 million of his &apos;Matrix&apos; earnings to the costume and special effects crews, quietly and without fanfare, and rides the New York subway like any other commuter.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Matt_Damon">He co-wrote &apos;Good Will Hunting&apos; with Ben Affleck as a Harvard class assignment, was repeatedly told it was too good to be written by unknowns, and both were paid $600,000 for the script.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ben_Affleck">After a career slump so severe it spawned the term &apos;Bennifer fatigue,&apos; he reinvented himself as a director with &apos;Gone Baby Gone&apos; and &apos;The Town&apos; before winning Best Picture for &apos;Argo.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="George_Clooney">He was rejected from the acting programme at Northern Kentucky University and spent years in failed TV pilots before ER made him a star, a story he regularly cites as proof that persistence beats early talent.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hugh_Jackman">He was cast as Wolverine two weeks into filming &apos;X-Men&apos; after Dougray Scott dropped out, then played the same character for 17 years across nine films, a record for a superhero role.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Russell_Crowe">He beat out Tom Hanks, Tom Cruise, and Mel Gibson for &apos;Gladiator&apos; and won the Oscar, despite the film having no finished script on the first day of shooting in Morocco.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Christian_Bale">He lost 63 pounds, down to 121 lbs, for &apos;The Machinist,&apos; then gained it all back plus muscle in six months for &apos;Batman Begins,&apos; setting a benchmark for physical transformation that few actors have matched.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Daniel_Day-Lewis">The only three-time Best Actor Oscar winner in history, he spent 18 months learning to use a left foot for &apos;My Left Foot&apos; and famously refused to break character throughout filming, including being pushed to set in a wheelchair.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Daniel_Craig">He arrived as the most controversial Bond casting in franchise history, with a petition to sack him before filming began, then delivered what many critics consider the best Bond performance in &apos;Casino Royale.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pierce_Brosnan">He was cast as James Bond in 1986 but contractually blocked by the show &apos;Remington Steele,&apos; which was renewed at the last minute, then had to wait nine more years before finally getting the role.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hugh_Grant">His career nearly ended after a 1995 arrest for lewd conduct in Los Angeles, but his self-deprecating &apos;I did a very bad thing&apos; interview with Jay Leno is credited with saving it.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Colin_Firth">His wet-shirt emergence from a lake as Mr. Darcy in the 1995 BBC &apos;Pride and Prejudice&apos; is ranked one of the greatest moments in British television history, and the image was later commemorated with a giant lake statue.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Liam_Neeson">He trained as an amateur boxer in Belfast before becoming an actor, and his &apos;particular set of skills&apos; speech in &apos;Taken&apos;, written in an afternoon, became one of the most quoted monologues of the 2000s.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ian_McKellen">He came out as gay in 1988 during a BBC radio debate on Section 28, an act of courage at the time, and has since said he refuses to act in any production for a country that criminalises homosexuality.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Patrick_Stewart">He was so unknown when cast as Captain Picard that the &apos;Star Trek: TNG&apos; crew assumed the bald Englishman was a joke, yet he went on to redefine the franchise and earn a knighthood.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Helen_Mirren">She won the Oscar, Emmy, Tony, and BAFTA, all four major English-language acting awards, and was made a Dame for services to drama, yet is perhaps best known for her bikini photos at 63.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Judi_Dench">She won her Oscar for &apos;Shakespeare in Love&apos; with just eight minutes of screen time as Queen Elizabeth I, one of the shortest winning performances in history, and has macular degeneration that leaves her nearly blind.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Maggie_Smith">She was filming &apos;Downton Abbey&apos; during chemotherapy for breast cancer, and many of the Dowager Countess&apos;s devastating one-liners were delivered between treatments.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Meryl_Streep">With 21 Academy Award nominations, far more than any other actor, she is known for total dialect immersion; for &apos;Sophie&apos;s Choice&apos; she learned both Polish and German, and co-stars reported she would answer only in character.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Julia_Roberts">Her fee for &apos;Erin Brockovich&apos;, $20 million, made her the first actress to earn that sum for a single film, and she spent three months working at the real Brockovich&apos;s law firm in preparation.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sandra_Bullock">She reportedly paid $1 million out of her own pocket to insure the troubled production of &apos;Speed,&apos; and later won the Oscar for &apos;The Blind Side&apos; while receiving a Razzie nomination in the same week.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Nicole_Kidman">After her divorce from Tom Cruise, she reportedly told friends &apos;at least I can wear heels now,&apos; and went on to win the Oscar for &apos;The Hours&apos; wearing a prosthetic nose.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Cate_Blanchett">She is one of very few actors to win Oscars in both leading and supporting categories, and co-directed Sydney Theatre Company while simultaneously shooting Hollywood blockbusters.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Charlize_Theron">A former ballet dancer who tore a knee ligament at 16, she pivoted to acting after being spotted arguing with a bank teller in a Los Angeles lobby: the manager called her a talent agent.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Halle_Berry">Her Best Actress win for &apos;Monster&apos;s Ball&apos; in 2002 made her the first, and as of 2026, still the only, Black woman to win the Academy Award for Best Actress.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Whoopi_Goldberg">One of the few EGOT winners, Emmy, Grammy, Oscar, Tony, she began her career performing stand-up in a fish-and-chips restaurant and later joined &apos;The View&apos; as a way to keep working during a Hollywood dry spell.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Reese_Witherspoon">She gained 15 pounds to play June Carter Cash in &apos;Walk the Line&apos; and did all her own singing; Cash&apos;s family said she captured June better than June captured herself.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jennifer_Aniston">She was told by an NBC executive early in her career that she was &apos;too fat&apos; for television; &apos;Friends&apos; debuted the following year and became one of the most-watched shows in history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jennifer_Lawrence">She became the second-youngest Best Actress Oscar winner in history for &apos;Silver Linings Playbook,&apos; beating out fellow nominees Meryl Streep and Jessica Chastain at age 22.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Anne_Hathaway">She was cast in &apos;The Princess Diaries&apos; after a casting director noticed she was the only actress who didn&apos;t fall out of her chair during auditions: she later won the Oscar for &apos;Les Misérables.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Scarlett_Johansson">The highest-grossing actress in box-office history, she played Black Widow for over a decade across the MCU and sued Disney in 2021 over &apos;Black Widow&apos;s&apos; streaming release, a suit settled out of court.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Natalie_Portman">She enrolled at Harvard to study psychology after &apos;Star Wars&apos; made her famous as a teenager, and her 2016 Harvard commencement speech on the relationship between fear and creativity went viral.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Drew_Barrymore">She appeared on the cover of People magazine at age seven as a cast member of &apos;E.T.,&apos; had completed rehab by age thirteen, and later rebuilt her career into a multi-platform media and beauty empire.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Cameron_Diaz">She was a model with no acting experience when she auditioned for &apos;The Mask&apos;, she didn&apos;t even know how to audition, and her natural chemistry with Jim Carrey launched her career.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Gwyneth_Paltrow">She won an Oscar for Shakespeare in Love but became equally famous for founding Goop, a lifestyle brand that once sold a jade egg with dubious wellness claims.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Demi_Moore">She shaved her head and earned a then-record $12.5 million for Striptease, but her most iconic role involved a pottery wheel and the song &apos;Unchained Melody&apos;.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sharon_Stone">A single scene in Basic Instinct made her a global star overnight and launched endless debates about what exactly happened during that police interrogation.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Salma_Hayek">She spent years fighting Harvey Weinstein to get her passion project made, a biopic about Frida Kahlo, and earned an Oscar nomination for playing the artist herself.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Penélope_Cruz">She became the first Spanish actress to win an Oscar, taking home the award for Vicky Cristina Barcelona after a string of acclaimed roles in Pedro Almodóvar films.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sophia_Loren">She was once jailed for tax evasion in Italy, but history remembers her as the first performer to win an Oscar for a non-English-language performance, in Two Women.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Brigitte_Bardot">She was so mobbed by paparazzi in Saint-Tropez that she effectively invented celebrity media culture, then walked away from stardom at 39 to campaign for animal rights.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Elizabeth_Taylor">She was the first actress paid $1 million for a single film, Cleopatra, and her violet eyes, eight marriages, and towering jewel collection became as legendary as her performances.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bette_Davis">She sued her own studio for the right to choose her own roles, a legal battle she lost but which eventually transformed how Hollywood treated its contract players.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Katharine_Hepburn">She holds the all-time record for most Best Actress Oscar wins with four, and wore trousers so defiantly in an era that banned them on studio lots that security once confiscated her clothes.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Judy_Garland">She recorded &apos;Somewhere Over the Rainbow&apos; at 16 and the song became one of the most beloved in history, though the studio tried to cut it from The Wizard of Oz as too slow.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Shirley_Temple">She was the number-one box office star in America for four straight years during the Great Depression, cheering up a nation while still in primary school.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lucille_Ball">She was so determined to star alongside her real-life husband that she bought out the studio, making her the first woman to run a major Hollywood production company.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mary_Tyler_Moore">Her sitcom&apos;s theme song, &apos;You&apos;re Gonna Make It After All&apos;, became an anthem for working women in the 1970s, and the hat-toss that opened it became one of TV&apos;s most iconic images.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Carrie_Fisher">She co-wrote the screenplay for When Harry Met Sally and turned her own struggles with addiction into a celebrated memoir, but the world knows her best as the princess who carried her own rescue.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mark_Hamill">After his iconic sci-fi role he reinvented himself as one of the most acclaimed voice actors in history, voicing the Joker in Batman: The Animated Series for decades.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Robert_Downey_Jr.">He went from a career-threatening prison stint to becoming the highest-paid actor in Hollywood, anchoring a cinematic universe that grossed over $20 billion.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Chris_Hemsworth">He beat out thousands of actors, including his own brother, to win the role of a Norse god, then transformed his physique so dramatically that the costume team had to rebuild his suit.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Chris_Evans_(actor)">He almost turned down the role of Captain America due to anxiety about the commitment, but the character&apos;s decade-long arc became one of the most beloved in superhero cinema.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Chris_Pratt">He went from playing a loveable schlub on a network sitcom to leading a cosmic superhero team, losing 60 pounds in six months for the audition that changed his career.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ryan_Reynolds">After a superhero film so poorly received that it was used as a punchline, he bought back the rights to the character and produced his own version, turning it into a billion-dollar franchise.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ryan_Gosling">He was cast in The Notebook specifically because the director thought he was &apos;not handsome&apos; enough: the film became one of the defining romance movies of the 2000s.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Idris_Elba">He hid his British accent so thoroughly while playing a Baltimore drug kingpin that American audiences were stunned to learn he was from London when he appeared at awards shows.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dwayne_Johnson">He was cut from the Canadian Football League with seven dollars in his pocket before pivoting to wrestling, where he became one of the most electrifying performers in the sport&apos;s history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Vin_Diesel">He wrote, directed, and starred in a short film just to get himself noticed in Hollywood: it worked, landing him a role in Saving Private Ryan and launching one of cinema&apos;s longest-running franchises.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jason_Statham">He was a competitive diver who represented England at the 1992 World Championships before a chance encounter with a fashion photographer set him on the path to action stardom.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jackie_Chan">He performs virtually all his own stunts and has broken nearly every bone in his body doing so: his outtake reels of failed and painful stunt attempts became a beloved cinema tradition.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bruce_Lee">He was so fast that film crews had to shoot him at 32 frames per second instead of 24 just to make his punches visible on screen.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jet_Li">He won China&apos;s national wushu championship five consecutive times starting at age 11, and turned down a role as a bodyguard for Richard Nixon to focus on martial arts.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Timothée_Chalamet">At 22 he became one of the youngest Best Actor Oscar nominees in history for Call Me by Your Name, kicking off a run of prestige roles that made him the defining leading man of his generation.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tom_Holland">He kept his casting as Spider-Man secret for months, revealing it accidentally on Instagram: the social-media slip became almost as famous as his first appearance in the suit.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Zendaya">She became the youngest person ever to win the Best Drama Actress Emmy, then won it again two years later, for playing a teenager navigating addiction in Euphoria.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Margot_Robbie">She produced and starred in Barbie, which grossed over $1.4 billion to become the highest-grossing film ever directed by a woman.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Emma_Stone">She taught herself to play drums for a key scene in La La Land and won her second Oscar for a film in which she plays multiple versions of the same character across different realities.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Emma_Watson">She turned down multiple major roles to complete her degree at Brown University, becoming one of the few blockbuster child stars to emerge from their franchise with both an education and their dignity intact.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Daniel_Radcliffe">He wore the same outfit every day for months to foil paparazzi photographers trying to sell shots of him, and has since built a remarkably varied indie film career far from his wand.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Rupert_Grint">He is so rarely recognized without his signature red hair that he once successfully went undetected at a Harry Potter exhibition, queuing with regular fans for over an hour.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kristen_Stewart">She was the first American actress to win a César Award, France&apos;s equivalent of the Oscar, for her role in Clouds of Sils Maria, silencing critics who had only known her from Twilight.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Robert_Pattinson">He was cast as a sparkly vampire largely on the strength of his performance in Harry Potter, then spent years doing experimental arthouse films to distance himself from the role before landing Batman.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mila_Kunis">She lied about her age at her audition for That &apos;70s Show, she was 14 when the role required 18, and kept the job for the entire run of the series.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ashton_Kutcher">He was discovered at a bar in Iowa by a model scout while attending college on a biochemical engineering scholarship, then became one of the first celebrities to reach one million Twitter followers.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mark_Wahlberg">He was a convicted criminal at 16 and a Calvin Klein underwear model at 20 before reinventing himself as a serious dramatic actor opposite the likes of Jack Nicholson.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Matthew_McConaughey">After years of formulaic rom-coms, he went on a deliberate hiatus, lost 47 pounds to play an AIDS patient, and won an Oscar, a career pivot that became known as the McConaissance.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Woody_Harrelson">He became famous playing a dim-witted barman, but his most daring performance may be True Detective, where he held his own against a co-star who famously stayed in character for eight months.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Owen_Wilson">His distinctive broken nose, the result of two separate incidents, became so much a part of his persona that he has never had it fixed, and his improvisational warmth made him one of comedy&apos;s most bankable stars.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Vince_Vaughn">His rapid-fire, improvisational delivery in Swingers, a micro-budget film shot in secret at real Hollywood venues, made him a star and created the template for a decade of bro comedies.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Will_Ferrell">His portrayal of a clueless elf who discovers he&apos;s human launched a Christmas movie franchise, but his most daring move was performing an entire Broadway show in character as his fictional country singer alter ego.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jack_Black">He formed the comedy rock band Tenacious D with Kyle Gass in 1994 and has maintained the side project, with genuine albums and tours, in parallel with a major Hollywood career for three decades.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Seth_Rogen">He started doing stand-up comedy at 13 in Vancouver, was hired to write for Judd Apatow at 19, and helped define a generation of raunchy-but-heartfelt comedies that dominated the 2000s.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Steve_Carell">His departure from The Office was kept so secret that most of the cast didn&apos;t know until they filmed the episode, producing genuinely tearful reactions that directors used in the final cut.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tina_Fey">She was the first female head writer in Saturday Night Live&apos;s history, created 30 Rock around her own experiences there, and wrote Mean Girls: all while critics debated whether women could be funny.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Amy_Poehler">She played the same optimistic government employee for seven seasons on Parks and Recreation, a character so beloved that fans genuinely mourned the show&apos;s end as if a real person had left their lives.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Melissa_McCarthy">She was rejected from Saturday Night Live, went on to co-write and star in Bridesmaids, received an Oscar nomination for it, and later hosted the very show that had turned her down.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kristen_Wiig">She joined SNL as a featured player and quietly became its most versatile performer, with over 100 original characters, before leaving to make Bridesmaids and redefine the Hollywood comedy landscape for women.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mindy_Kaling">She was the only woman and only person of color writing on The Office, where she also played a character, and went on to create, write, produce, and star in her own network show simultaneously.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Steven_Spielberg">He was rejected by USC&apos;s film school twice, snuck onto the Universal Studios lot to observe productions, and eventually talked his way into a directing deal: before making Jaws, which invented the summer blockbuster.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Martin_Scorsese">He has been nominated for the Best Director Oscar eight times and won once, for The Departed, despite being considered one of the greatest filmmakers who ever lived.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Quentin_Tarantino">He wrote the screenplays for Pulp Fiction and True Romance while working in a video rental store, drawing on an encyclopedic knowledge of cinema absorbed entirely outside of any film school.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Christopher_Nolan">He shot his debut feature Memento over weekends for under $10,000, then used it to convince studios to hand him the Batman franchise, and eventually a blank cheque for original blockbuster ideas.</hint>
  <hint wiki="James_Cameron">He was a truck driver before teaching himself filmmaking, and twice held the record for the highest-grossing film of all time: first with Titanic, then with Avatar.</hint>
  <hint wiki="George_Lucas">He sold the Star Wars merchandising rights to himself rather than the studio in lieu of a higher directing fee, a decision worth billions that changed how Hollywood thought about intellectual property forever.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Stanley_Kubrick">He was so obsessed with perfection that he filmed one scene in The Shining 127 times, and kept the specific lens he used for Barry Lyndon a closely guarded secret for years.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Francis_Ford_Coppola">He was nearly fired from The Godfather multiple times during production, but the finished film went on to win three Oscars and redefine what American cinema could be.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tim_Burton">He was fired from Disney as an animator because his drawings were considered too dark and unsettling, then returned as one of Hollywood&apos;s most commercially successful directors of dark, unsettling films.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Wes_Anderson">His films are so visually distinctive, centered compositions, pastel palettes, precisely symmetrical frames, that his aesthetic has been parodied in hundreds of internet videos and even a fake AI-generated trailer.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Spike_Lee">He financed She&apos;s Gotta Have It by maxing out credit cards and calling in every favor he had in Brooklyn, then turned the film&apos;s success into a platform for unflinching commentary on race in America.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Peter_Jackson">He made his name with gleefully gory low-budget horror comedies in New Zealand before convincing a studio to let him film all three Lord of the Rings movies simultaneously.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ron_Howard">He grew up on screen as a child actor, stepped behind the camera, and won the Best Director Oscar for A Beautiful Mind: one of the few people to succeed fully on both sides of the lens.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Woody_Allen">He wrote, directed, and starred in a film almost every single year for five decades, a prolific output that also includes multiple Grammy-winning comedy albums recorded before he ever made a movie.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jordan_Peele">He spent a decade as one half of a sketch comedy duo before writing and directing Get Out, which won him the Oscar for Best Original Screenplay: the first Black writer to win that award solo.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Greta_Gerwig">Her Lady Bird was the first solo-directed film by a woman to receive a Best Picture Oscar nomination, then her Barbie smashed box office records while sparking a global cultural conversation.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sofia_Coppola">Growing up on her father&apos;s film sets, she absorbed filmmaking by osmosis, then made Lost in Translation, a film so understated it earned her an Oscar for Best Original Screenplay.</hint>
  <hint wiki="J._J._Abrams">He created a mystery-box approach to storytelling so influential, seeding unresolvable questions to keep audiences hooked, that it became both a filmmaking strategy and a cultural critique.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Guillermo_del_Toro">He kept a notebook of ideas and sketches for decades before turning them into films: the notebook itself was displayed as an art object when it was eventually published.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hayao_Miyazaki">He has retired and un-retired multiple times, but each farewell seemed to produce another masterpiece, including The Boy and the Heron, made in his eighties, which won the Academy Award for Best Animated Feature.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Beyoncé">She performed at the Super Bowl halftime show while secretly pregnant, and her visual album Lemonade, released as a complete surprise, redefined what a pop album release could be.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jay-Z">He built a business empire worth over $2.5 billion spanning music, streaming, sports management, and alcohol, becoming the first rapper to become a billionaire.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Rihanna">She turned a Super Bowl halftime performance into a pregnancy announcement watched by 120 million people, and her Fenty Beauty line, built on radical shade inclusivity, revolutionized the cosmetics industry.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Taylor_Swift">She re-recorded her first six albums to reclaim ownership of her music after a catalogue dispute, turning a legal strategy into a pop cultural movement that sent old songs back to number one.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Adele">Her album 21 spent 24 non-consecutive weeks at number one in the United States and sold over 30 million copies worldwide, making it one of the best-selling albums of the 21st century.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lady_Gaga">She arrived at the 2010 VMAs in a dress made entirely of raw meat, but also composed and performed a Broadway-quality score for A Star Is Born, earning an Oscar for Best Original Song.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Katy_Perry">She became the first artist to have five number-one singles from a single album, Teenage Dream, matching a record previously held only by Michael Jackson.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ariana_Grande">Her whistle-register notes are among the highest ever recorded in pop, and her ponytail became so iconic that costume shops stock it as a standalone Halloween accessory.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Billie_Eilish">She recorded her debut album in her brother&apos;s childhood bedroom, became the first person born in the 2000s to top the charts, and won all four major Grammy categories in a single night at age 18.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dua_Lipa">Her album Future Nostalgia was recorded before the pandemic and released into lockdown, where its disco-inflected escapism became the soundtrack to a world stuck indoors.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Olivia_Rodrigo">She wrote &apos;drivers license&apos; about a heartbreak and released it as a debut single: it shattered Spotify&apos;s single-day streaming record and spent eight weeks at number one before she had a full album out.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sabrina_Carpenter">She spent years as a Disney Channel regular before &apos;Espresso&apos;, a fizzy, self-penned earworm, went globally viral in 2024 and made her one of pop&apos;s biggest breakout stars.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Miley_Cyrus">She performed a notorious twerking routine at the VMAs that generated more tweets per minute than any previous event, then followed it with an album that revealed a genuinely powerful rock voice.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Selena_Gomez">She quietly became the most-followed person on Instagram for years while managing a kidney transplant in private, and her candid discussions of mental health helped shift public conversation around celebrity wellness.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Demi_Lovato">She publicly documented her struggles with eating disorders and addiction in a documentary series, turning her own story into a platform for mental health advocacy long before it was a mainstream celebrity cause.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Christina_Aguilera">She was cast alongside Britney Spears on The Mickey Mouse Club as a child, then out-vocalized virtually every contemporary with a five-octave range that earned her the nickname &apos;the Voice&apos;.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Britney_Spears">The opening bars of &apos;...Baby One More Time&apos; are among the most recognizable in pop history, and her 2007 public breakdown, and the conservatorship that followed, sparked a worldwide Free Britney movement years later.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jennifer_Lopez">She was paid $1 million for Selena in 1997, making her the first Latina actress to earn that figure, then crossed over into music and became simultaneously one of Hollywood&apos;s biggest stars and pop&apos;s most durable hitmakers.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mariah_Carey">She owns Christmas: her 1994 song &apos;All I Want for Christmas Is You&apos; returns to number one every December, making her the first artist in history to top the charts in four separate decades with a single song.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Celine_Dion">She sang &apos;My Heart Will Go On&apos; in a single take and reportedly disliked it, but it became the best-selling physical single by a female artist in history and the signature song of the 1990s.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Shakira">She taught herself to play guitar as a child in Colombia and co-wrote most of her own material in two languages: her hips and her honesty both became internationally recognized cultural touchstones.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pink_(singer)">She has performed some of the most dangerous aerial acrobatics in pop concert history, including suspended harness routines in pouring rain, doing them live, without a safety net of lip-syncing.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Alicia_Keys">She graduated high school at 16 as valedictorian while simultaneously recording her debut album, which debuted at number one and made her the best-selling new artist of 2001.</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_Legend">He is one of the few people to have achieved EGOT status, winning an Emmy, Grammy, Oscar, and Tony, and he completed the set at just 39 years old.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bruno_Mars">He grew up performing in a family band in Hawaii, impersonating Elvis at age four, and later became one of the last major pop artists to write, produce, and perform virtually all of his own material.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Justin_Bieber">He was discovered at 13 via YouTube videos his mother posted, making him the first major pop star whose career was entirely launched by social media rather than a traditional record deal.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Justin_Timberlake">He ripped Janet Jackson&apos;s costume at the Super Bowl halftime show in 2004, an incident that ignited a national debate about media double standards; Jackson&apos;s career suffered while his continued to soar.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ed_Sheeran">He slept on the London Underground and on friends&apos; sofas for a year while trying to break through, before a chance connection with Jamie Foxx led to his first big break.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Harry_Styles">He auditioned as a solo act on The X Factor, was eliminated, then was placed into a group with four other rejected soloists, a decision that created one of the best-selling boy bands in history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Shawn_Mendes">He built a following by posting six-second cover videos on Vine as a teenager, becoming one of the first musicians to convert a social media presence directly into a record deal and a number-one album.</hint>
  <hint wiki="The_Weeknd">He uploaded his first three mixtapes anonymously to YouTube with no press, no label, and no real name attached, amassing millions of streams before anyone knew who he was.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Drake_(musician)">He was best known as a teenage wheelchair user on a Canadian high school drama before reinventing himself as a rapper and becoming one of the most-streamed artists in Spotify&apos;s history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kanye_West">He was told by nearly every major label that a producer couldn&apos;t be a rapper, so he famously recorded vocals for &apos;Through the Wire&apos; with his jaw wired shut after a near-fatal car accident.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kendrick_Lamar">His album To Pimp a Butterfly was the first rap album to win the Pulitzer Prize for Music, and his Super Bowl halftime show in 2025 became one of the most discussed in the event&apos;s history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Eminem">He was a white rapper from Detroit who was told he&apos;d never make it in hip-hop, then released The Slim Shady LP and sold over 1.8 million copies in its first week.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Snoop_Dogg">He was arrested on murder charges the same week his debut album Doggystyle was released, the charges were eventually dropped, and the album went on to sell four million copies in its first year.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dr._Dre">He produced both Snoop Dogg&apos;s and Eminem&apos;s debut albums, effectively launching two of the biggest careers in hip-hop history, then sold his Beats Electronics company to Apple for $3 billion.</hint>
  <hint wiki="50_Cent">He was shot nine times on his doorstep in 2000, survived, was dropped by his label, and used the story as the foundation of a mixtape buzz campaign that led to one of the best-selling debut albums of the decade.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tupac_Shakur">He recorded so prolifically that new albums were released for years after his death, and his hologram appeared onstage at Coachella in 2012, reigniting debates about artistic legacy and whether he had faked his death.</hint>
  <hint wiki="The_Notorious_B.I.G.">He grew up selling crack on a Brooklyn street corner, taught himself to freestyle, and within a few years had crafted Ready to Die, considered one of the greatest debut albums in the history of hip-hop.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lil_Wayne">He released &apos;Tha Carter III&apos; in 2008, which debuted at #1 and sold over a million copies in its first week, cementing him as the self-proclaimed &apos;Best Rapper Alive.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Travis_Scott">His Astroworld album turned a Houston fairground nostalgia trip into a cultural phenomenon, complete with a rollercoaster named after him at the actual Six Flags.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Post_Malone">He went from a Dallas teenager recording in his friend&apos;s closet to having &apos;Congratulations&apos; rack up billions of streams before his debut album even dropped.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Cardi_B">She became the first solo female rapper to win the Grammy for Best Rap Album, taking it home for &apos;Invasion of Privacy&apos; in 2019.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Nicki_Minaj">She held the record for the most entries on the Billboard Hot 100 by a female artist for years, thanks in part to a seemingly endless string of guest verses.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Megan_Thee_Stallion">Her &apos;Savage (Remix)&apos; with Beyoncé hit #1 in 2020 even as she was finishing her degree in health administration at Texas Southern University.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ice_Cube">As a founding member of N.W.A, he wrote most of the lyrics for &apos;Straight Outta Compton,&apos; the album that scared the FBI enough to send the group an official warning letter.</hint>
  <hint wiki="LL_Cool_J">He released &apos;Rock the Bells&apos; at 16 and became one of the first rappers to prove the genre could sustain a decades-long career; his initials stand for &apos;Ladies Love Cool James.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pharrell_Williams">He and his Neptunes partner Chad Hugo won Producer of the Year at the Grammys twice, and his song &apos;Happy&apos; from Despicable Me 2 became one of the best-selling singles of all time.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Usher_(musician)">His 2004 album &apos;Confessions&apos; spent 11 weeks at #1 and sold over 20 million copies, and he discovered and mentored Justin Bieber as a teenager.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Chris_Brown">At 16 he became the first male artist since Stevie Wonder to debut at #1 with a debut single, and he is widely considered one of the most technically skilled dancers in pop history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Frank_Ocean">He released &apos;Channel Orange&apos; after a Tumblr post quietly disclosing a past relationship with a man, a rare, understated coming-out that reshaped conversations about queerness in R&amp;B.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bad_Bunny">The Puerto Rican trap star became the most-streamed artist on Spotify globally three years in a row (2020-2022), the first non-English-language act to achieve that.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Doja_Cat">Her song &apos;Say So&apos; went viral via TikTok before being officially released, a textbook case of internet-era music stardom that she followed with a Nicki Minaj remix that sent it to #1.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lana_Del_Rey">Her breakout video &apos;Video Games&apos;, shot on a flip camera and self-uploaded to YouTube in 2011, went viral and landed her a major-label deal almost overnight.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bruce_Springsteen">His 1975 album &apos;Born to Run&apos; earned him simultaneous covers of Time and Newsweek, and his legendary live shows often run four hours, making him synonymous with rock as communal endurance.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mick_Jagger">As the Rolling Stones&apos; frontman since 1962, he has performed across six decades and reportedly turned down a knighthood once before eventually accepting Sir Mick status in 2003.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Keith_Richards">He wrote &apos;Satisfaction&apos; in his sleep, literally woke up, recorded the riff, and fell back asleep, and his lifestyle inspired Johnny Depp&apos;s portrayal of Captain Jack Sparrow.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ringo_Starr">Despite being the butt of &apos;worst Beatle&apos; jokes, he was voted the greatest rock drummer of all time by Rolling Stone readers in 2011, with legends like Dave Grohl citing his feel.</hint>
  <hint wiki="George_Harrison">Often called &apos;the quiet Beatle,&apos; he wrote &apos;Something,&apos; which Frank Sinatra called the greatest love song of 50 years, and organized the first major rock benefit concert in 1971.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Eric_Clapton">1960s London fans spray-painted &apos;Clapton is God&apos; on Underground walls, and he is the only three-time inductee into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame: solo artist, Yardbird, and Cream member.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Billy_Joel">He played the final concert ever held at Shea Stadium in 2008, closing with &apos;Piano Man&apos;, a song he wrote while playing piano under a pseudonym in an LA bar when his career had stalled.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Neil_Young">He earned the nickname &apos;the Godfather of Grunge&apos; for his distorted guitar influence on a generation, and famously pulled his entire catalog from Spotify over a COVID misinformation dispute.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Joni_Mitchell">Her 1971 album &apos;Blue&apos; is frequently ranked the greatest album ever made, and she invented over 50 open guitar tunings because childhood polio left her hand unable to form standard chord shapes.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Cher">She has had number-one hits in six consecutive decades, a record no other solo artist holds, from &apos;I Got You Babe&apos; in the 1960s to &apos;Believe&apos; in the 1990s, the latter pioneering the Auto-Tune effect.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Diana_Ross">As lead of the Supremes she scored 12 number-one hits, more than any 1960s act except the Beatles, and was later nominated for an Oscar for playing Billie Holiday.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ray_Charles">He fused gospel, blues, and country so controversially that Georgia initially banned him, before later naming &apos;Georgia on My Mind&apos; the official state song.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Johnny_Cash">He performed at Folsom Prison in 1968 in a concert that revived his flagging career, and dressed entirely in black as a protest against poverty, turning a wardrobe choice into a political statement.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Willie_Nelson">He wrote &apos;Crazy&apos;, one of the most recorded songs in history, and sold it to Patsy Cline when his own unconventional vocal style couldn&apos;t get radio play.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dolly_Parton">She secretly funded the Moderna COVID vaccine research and declined a state statue of herself, saying she hadn&apos;t earned it: while her song &apos;I Will Always Love You&apos; was written as a business breakup letter to her mentor.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Garth_Brooks">He became the best-selling solo artist in U.S. history, outselling Elvis Presley, and his alter-ego &apos;Chris Gaines&apos;, a fictional rock star invented for a film project, remains one of pop culture&apos;s strangest career detours.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Shania_Twain">&apos;Come On Over&apos; is the best-selling country album of all time and the best-selling album by any female artist in any genre, with over 40 million copies sold.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Carrie_Underwood">She won American Idol in 2005 and became its commercially most successful contestant, and her debut single &apos;Before He Cheats&apos; spent 28 weeks at number one: the longest run by a debut country single.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Luke_Bryan">He racked up more number-one singles on the Billboard Country Airplay chart than any other artist in the 2010s, and took over guardianship of his nephew and niece after losing both his brother and sister-in-law.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Reba_McEntire">She survived the worst disaster in country music history when seven band members died in a 1991 plane crash, returned to touring within months, and later starred in a sitcom that ran for six seasons.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Faith_Hill">Her &apos;Breathe&apos; album sold over 8 million copies and made her one of the few country artists to cross over to mainstream pop in the late 1990s.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tim_McGraw">His &apos;Live Like You Were Dying&apos; won the Grammy for Best Country Song in 2005, and he proposed to Faith Hill while on tour together in 1996.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Morgan_Wallen">His double album &apos;Dangerous&apos; spent a record 10 consecutive weeks at number one on the Billboard 200, the longest streak for any country album.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lizzo">She played James Madison&apos;s 200-year-old crystal flute, borrowed from the Library of Congress, during a sold-out Washington D.C. show, the first time the instrument had been played in over a century.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lorde">She was 16 when &apos;Royals&apos; became the first solo female artist born in the 1990s to top the Billboard Hot 100, a wry critique of hip-hop wealth fantasies from a suburban Auckland teenager.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Halsey_(singer)">She self-released music on SoundCloud as a teenager and built a fanbase before she had a record deal, eventually headlining arenas and releasing albums that spanned every genre.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sia_(musician)">She hid her face behind a giant bow-and-wig costume for years, and her &apos;Chandelier&apos; music video featuring dancer Maddie Ziegler has over a billion YouTube views.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Amy_Winehouse">Her album &apos;Back to Black&apos; won five Grammy Awards in 2008, including Record, Song, and Album of the Year, a record for a British female artist that stood for years.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Roger_Waters">He conceived &apos;The Wall&apos; as a metaphor for his own emotional alienation, and the 1980-81 tour featured an actual 40-foot wall built across the stage mid-show.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ozzy_Osbourne">He was fired from Black Sabbath and proceeded to have a bigger solo career, and became tabloid legend when he bit the head off a bat thrown onstage at a 1982 concert.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Axl_Rose">Guns N&apos; Roses&apos; &apos;Appetite for Destruction&apos; is the best-selling debut album in U.S. history, with over 30 million copies sold worldwide.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Slash_(musician)">His top-hat-and-cigarette silhouette is one of rock&apos;s most recognizable icons, and the opening riff of &apos;Sweet Child O&apos; Mine&apos;, written in under a minute as a warmup exercise, became one of the most-played guitar riffs ever.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bono">He negotiated directly with world leaders as part of his ONE Campaign, securing billions in aid for Africa, and U2&apos;s &apos;The Joshua Tree&apos; made the Irish band the biggest rock act in the world in 1987.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sting_(musician)">After leaving The Police at their commercial peak, he spent years advocating for Amazon rainforest preservation and his claim of tantric discipline became a cultural punchline that somehow only increased his mystique.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Phil_Collins">He played Live Aid twice in 1985, once in London and once in Philadelphia the same day, after flying across the Atlantic on Concorde, and his &apos;In the Air Tonight&apos; drum fill is one of the most air-drummed moments in pop history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lenny_Kravitz">He wrote, produced, and played nearly every instrument on his debut album alone in a New York apartment, and won four consecutive Grammys for Best Male Rock Vocal Performance, a record that still stands.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Carlos_Santana">His Woodstock performance in 1969 is one of rock history&apos;s most celebrated sets, and thirty years later his &apos;Supernatural&apos; album won nine Grammys in a single night.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Quincy_Jones">He produced Michael Jackson&apos;s &apos;Thriller,&apos; &apos;Off the Wall,&apos; and &apos;Bad&apos;, three of the best-selling albums ever, and with 28 Grammy Awards is among the most decorated individuals in the ceremony&apos;s history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Luciano_Pavarotti">His 1990 performance of &apos;Nessun Dorma&apos; at the BBC&apos;s World Cup broadcast introduced opera to hundreds of millions of TV viewers, making the aria a sporting-event staple.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Andrea_Bocelli">Blind since the age of 12, he has sold over 90 million records, more than any classical or operatic artist in history, with a crossover career that kept him atop both classical and pop charts.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Yo-Yo_Ma">He founded the Silk Road Ensemble blending Central Asian, Chinese, and Western musical traditions, and played at Barack Obama&apos;s inauguration in 2009 in temperatures so cold the performance had to be pre-recorded.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lin-Manuel_Miranda">He conceived &apos;Hamilton&apos; while reading a biography on vacation and performed the first song at the White House for President Obama before the show won 11 Tonys.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Andrew_Lloyd_Webber">He composed &apos;The Phantom of the Opera,&apos; the longest-running show in Broadway history, which ran for 35 years, and co-wrote &apos;Jesus Christ Superstar&apos; with Tim Rice before age 25.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hans_Zimmer">He scored &apos;The Lion King,&apos; &apos;Gladiator,&apos; &apos;Inception,&apos; and &apos;Interstellar,&apos; pioneering non-Western instruments and electronic synthesis in blockbuster film scores.</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_Williams">He composed the themes for &apos;Star Wars,&apos; &apos;Indiana Jones,&apos; &apos;Jaws,&apos; and &apos;Harry Potter&apos;, a run so ubiquitous that a single note can identify each film, and holds 54 Academy Award nominations.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ludwig_van_Beethoven">He composed his Ninth Symphony, including the &apos;Ode to Joy&apos;, after he was completely deaf, and famously turned around at the premiere to see the standing ovation he couldn&apos;t hear.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Wolfgang_Amadeus_Mozart">He composed his first symphony at age 8 and over 600 works before dying at 35, and his &apos;Don Giovanni&apos; overture was reportedly handed to musicians as the audience was still taking their seats.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Johann_Sebastian_Bach">He fathered 20 children and still produced over 1,000 compositions, but his music was largely forgotten after his death until Felix Mendelssohn revived the &apos;St. Matthew Passion&apos; in 1829.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pyotr_Ilyich_Tchaikovsky">His ballets; &apos;Swan Lake,&apos; &apos;The Nutcracker,&apos; and &apos;Sleeping Beauty&apos;: defined classical ballet for Western audiences, and his 1812 Overture famously calls for real cannon fire.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Frédéric_Chopin">He performed publicly only about 30 times in his entire life, preferring salon settings to concert halls, yet his études and nocturnes became the foundation of modern piano technique.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Antonio_Vivaldi">He wrote over 500 concertos and taught at a Venetian orphanage whose all-girl orchestra became one of the most celebrated in Europe.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kobe_Bryant">He scored 81 points in a single NBA game in 2006, the second-highest individual scoring game in history, and won an Academy Award for Best Animated Short Film in 2018.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Shaquille_O&apos;Neal">His combination of 7-foot-1 height and 325 pounds made him arguably the most physically dominant player the NBA has ever seen, and he also had a platinum-selling rap single while still an active player.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Magic_Johnson">His 6-foot-9 point guard frame broke every assumption about the position, and his 1991 announcement that he had contracted HIV, at a time of enormous stigma, changed public understanding of the disease.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Larry_Bird">He won three consecutive NBA MVP awards and made Celtics-Lakers a cultural rivalry that helped save the NBA from low ratings and tape-delayed Finals coverage.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kareem_Abdul-Jabbar">His skyhook, an unstoppable one-handed shot no defense ever solved, remained effective across a 20-year career, and he held the NBA&apos;s all-time scoring record from 1984 until LeBron James surpassed it.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Stephen_Curry">He revolutionized basketball by making the three-pointer the central offensive weapon, and his 2016 MVP was the first unanimous vote in NBA history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kevin_Durant">His 7-foot frame with a shooting guard&apos;s skill set made him a position-less player before the term was common, and his decision to join the Golden State Warriors sparked one of the most polarizing debates in modern sports.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Giannis_Antetokounmpo">He went from selling trinkets on the streets of Athens as a teenager to winning two NBA MVP awards and an NBA championship before turning 27, earning the nickname &apos;The Greek Freak.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Allen_Iverson">He was the first player under 6-foot-1 to win an NBA MVP award, and his crossover dribble, cornrow braids, and tattoos made him the avatar of a generation&apos;s basketball identity.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Charles_Barkley">Listed at 6-foot-4, he dominated players much taller through sheer physicality, and his Nike ad declaring &apos;I am not a role model&apos; became one of sports history&apos;s most debated statements.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dennis_Rodman">He led the league in rebounding seven consecutive seasons and won five championships, while also making solo diplomatic trips to North Korea and developing a personal friendship with Kim Jong-un.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Caitlin_Clark">She became the all-time leading scorer in NCAA Division I basketball history, men&apos;s or women&apos;s, breaking Pete Maravich&apos;s 53-year-old record, and her move to the WNBA shattered the league&apos;s viewership records.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tom_Brady">He was the 199th pick in the 2000 NFL Draft, taken after six other quarterbacks, and went on to win seven Super Bowl rings, more than any franchise in history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Peyton_Manning">He was the first player to win Super Bowls with two different franchises as starting quarterback, and his forehead-slapping, audible-calling offense at the line of scrimmage changed how the entire position operates.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Patrick_Mahomes">By age 28 he had already won four Super Bowl MVP awards, and his sidearm and no-look passes have expanded the vocabulary of what a quarterback throw can look like.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Aaron_Rodgers">His Hail Mary to beat Dallas in 2016, thrown off his back foot as he was being tackled, is one of the most replayed moments in NFL playoff history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Joe_Montana">He never threw an interception in four Super Bowl appearances, going 4-0, and his final-drive against Cincinnati with 3:10 left and no timeouts is still considered the greatest clutch performance in NFL history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jerry_Rice">He holds virtually every significant NFL receiving record by margins considered unbreakable, and ran routes so precisely that defensive backs said they could set a watch by his cuts.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Brett_Favre">He started 297 consecutive regular-season games, a record for any position player, and his gunslinger style produced three consecutive MVP awards alongside some of the most memorable interceptions ever thrown.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Travis_Kelce">He is the most productive tight end in NFL postseason history, and his relationship with Taylor Swift in 2023 turned his already high profile into a cross-cultural phenomenon.</hint>
  <hint wiki="O._J._Simpson">He was the first running back to rush for 2,000 yards in a single NFL season (1973), and his 1995 murder trial became one of the most watched televised events in American history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="David_Beckham">He scored from the halfway line on the Premier League&apos;s opening day of 1996, a 57-yard lob that became one of football&apos;s most iconic goals, and was the first British player to win league titles in four different countries.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Zinedine_Zidane">His volley in the 2002 Champions League Final is consistently voted the greatest goal in the competition&apos;s history, and he led France to both the World Cup and European Championship in back-to-back years.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ronaldinho">He scored two curling free-kicks against Real Madrid and received a standing ovation from the opposing Bernabeu crowd: one of the rarest moments in football history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ronaldo_(Brazilian_footballer)">He scored twice in the 2002 World Cup Final after two years barely playing due to mysterious seizures, and his dominance was so total that &apos;Ronaldo&apos; had to become &apos;CR7&apos; just to distinguish a later player.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Neymar">He became the world&apos;s most expensive footballer at 222 million euros in 2017, and was the fulcrum of the MSN trio with Messi and Suarez at Barcelona that won the treble in 2015.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kylian_Mbappé">He became only the second teenager in history, after Pelé, to score in a World Cup Final, doing so in France&apos;s 2018 triumph at age 19.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mohamed_Salah">He scored 32 Premier League goals in 2017-18, breaking the record for a 38-game season, and has been notably vocal about being a Muslim in European football.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Megan_Rapinoe">She scored two goals in the 2019 Women&apos;s World Cup Final and won both the Golden Boot and Golden Ball in the same tournament, and was the first white athlete and first woman to kneel during the national anthem.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mia_Hamm">She was the world&apos;s all-time leading goal scorer in international soccer, men&apos;s or women&apos;s, at the time of her retirement, and was the first female footballer to become a mainstream American sports icon.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Rafael_Nadal">He won the French Open 14 times, a number so surreal that the main court at Roland Garros was renamed in his honor while he was still winning on it.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Novak_Djokovic">He holds the record for the most Grand Slam singles titles in men&apos;s tennis history, and was deported from Australia before the 2022 Open for refusing COVID vaccination, turning a sports story into a global political flashpoint.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Venus_Williams">She was the first Black woman ranked number one in the Open Era, and her campaign alongside her family to force equal prize money at Wimbledon succeeded in 2007.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Billie_Jean_King">She beat Bobby Riggs in the &apos;Battle of the Sexes&apos; in 1973 before 90 million TV viewers, a match that became a landmark moment for gender equality in sports.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Naomi_Osaka">She won four Major titles before turning 24, and her 2021 French Open withdrawal, disclosing depression and anxiety, ignited a global conversation about athlete mental health.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Carlos_Alcaraz">He became the youngest player in history to reach the ATP world number one ranking at 19, and his game draws comparisons to Federer, Nadal, and Djokovic simultaneously.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jack_Nicklaus">He won 18 Major championships, a record considered the sport&apos;s ultimate benchmark, and designed over 300 golf courses worldwide after retiring.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Arnold_Palmer">He transformed golf from a country-club pursuit into a televised mass sport in the 1960s, and the drink named after him, half iced tea, half lemonade, appears on menus worldwide.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Rory_McIlroy">He won four Major championships before turning 26, and has been the central figure in the PGA Tour vs. LIV Golf conflict, choosing to stay with the established tour when many peers defected.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sidney_Crosby">He was selected first overall in 2005: the year the NHL cancelled its entire season, known as the &apos;Crosby Sweepstakes&apos;, and his overtime goal in the 2010 Olympics gold medal game is the most-watched moment in Canadian sports TV history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Alexander_Ovechkin">He broke Wayne Gretzky&apos;s all-time NHL goal-scoring record in 2023, a mark that had stood for 30 years, and has led the league in goals scored nine times.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mario_Lemieux">He scored a goal in five different ways in a single game in 1988, a feat never replicated, and later bought the Pittsburgh Penguins to save them from bankruptcy, then came out of retirement to play for the team he owned.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Derek_Jeter">He made &apos;The Flip&apos;, a no-look shovel pass to nail Jeremy Giambi at the plate in the 2001 ALDS: one of the most instinctive defensive plays in playoff history, and his 3,000th hit was a home run.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mickey_Mantle">He hit a home run in 1953 measured at 565 feet, coining the term &apos;tape-measure home run&apos;, and is considered the greatest what-if player in baseball history due to chronic knee injuries.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hank_Aaron">He held baseball&apos;s all-time home run record for 33 years, breaking Babe Ruth&apos;s mark in 1974 while receiving death threats, and preserved the racist hate mail he received to donate to the Baseball Hall of Fame.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Willie_Mays">His over-the-shoulder catch in the 1954 World Series, sprinting with his back to the plate to snag a 425-foot drive, is simply called &apos;The Catch&apos; and is considered the greatest defensive play in baseball history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Joe_DiMaggio">He hit safely in 56 consecutive games in 1941, a record statisticians rank among the most improbable achievements in all of sports, and sent roses to Marilyn Monroe&apos;s grave three times a week for 20 years after her death.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Barry_Bonds">His 2001 season of 73 home runs and a .515 on-base percentage is statistically the greatest offensive season in baseball history, and he was intentionally walked 120 times in 2004 as managers simply refused to pitch to him.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Shohei_Ohtani">He is the only player in MLB history to be a legitimate ace starter and a legitimate cleanup hitter simultaneously, and in 2023 signed the largest contract in sports history, $700 million over 10 years, with the Los Angeles Dodgers.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mike_Trout">Widely regarded as the best baseball player of his generation, he won three American League MVP awards by age 27 while playing his entire career for the Los Angeles Angels.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Floyd_Mayweather_Jr.">Retired with a perfect 50-0 professional record, his 2015 fight against Manny Pacquiao became the highest-grossing boxing match in history at the time.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Manny_Pacquiao">The only boxer to win world titles in eight different weight divisions, he later served as a senator and presidential candidate in the Philippines.</hint>
  <hint wiki="George_Foreman">He lost the &apos;Rumble in the Jungle&apos; to Muhammad Ali in 1974, then made a stunning comeback to reclaim the heavyweight title at age 45, and later sold more than 100 million George Foreman Grills.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Evander_Holyfield">A four-time heavyweight champion best remembered for two brutal fights with Mike Tyson, the second of which ended when Tyson infamously bit off a chunk of his ear.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Conor_McGregor">The first UFC fighter to hold titles in two weight classes simultaneously, he crossed over to boxing in 2017 for a mega-fight against Floyd Mayweather that generated over $600 million.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ronda_Rousey">She dominated women&apos;s MMA so thoroughly that her first 12 UFC fights lasted a combined total of under 15 minutes, and she is widely credited with making women&apos;s MMA mainstream.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lewis_Hamilton">He matched and then surpassed Michael Schumacher&apos;s all-time record of seven Formula 1 World Championship titles, becoming the sport&apos;s most decorated driver in history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dale_Earnhardt">Known as &apos;The Intimidator,&apos; he won seven NASCAR Cup Series championships but died tragically in a last-lap crash at the 2001 Daytona 500, sending shockwaves through the sport.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Max_Verstappen">He clinched his first Formula 1 championship in 2021 on the final lap of the final race in controversial circumstances, then dominated the sport with a record-breaking 19 wins in a single season.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Michael_Phelps">The most decorated Olympian of all time with 23 gold medals, he became a legend at the 2008 Beijing Games when he won eight gold medals in a single Olympics.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Katie_Ledecky">She has shattered her own world records in long-distance freestyle swimming multiple times, often winning races by margins that make her competitors look like they are in a different event.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Simone_Biles">Considered the greatest gymnast of all time, she has a signature vault named after her that is rated so dangerous the scoring code initially discouraged others from attempting it.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Nadia_Comăneci">At the 1976 Montreal Olympics she became the first gymnast ever to be awarded a perfect score of 10.0, a feat so unprecedented that the scoreboard could only display &apos;1.00.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mary_Lou_Retton">She vaulted into American hearts at the 1984 Los Angeles Olympics with a perfect 10 on her final vault, clinching the all-around gold medal by the slimmest possible margin.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Michelle_Kwan">One of the most beloved American figure skaters ever, she won nine U.S. championships and five World titles but famously never captured the Olympic gold medal that eluded her twice.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tonya_Harding">Her career was derailed by the 1994 scandal in which her ex-husband arranged an attack on rival Nancy Kerrigan&apos;s knee before the U.S. Figure Skating Championships.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Shaun_White">Nicknamed &apos;The Flying Tomato&apos; for his wild red hair, he won three Olympic halfpipe gold medals in snowboarding and is the only athlete to win gold at five consecutive X Games in a single discipline.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tony_Hawk">He landed the first-ever documented 900, two-and-a-half aerial rotations on a skateboard, at the 1999 X Games, a trick many thought was physically impossible.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lance_Armstrong">He won seven consecutive Tour de France titles from 1999 to 2005 after surviving testicular cancer, only to have all his titles stripped when he confessed to a systematic doping program.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hulk_Hogan">The face of professional wrestling&apos;s 1980s boom, his signature leg drop finishing move and &apos;Hulkamania&apos; persona helped transform the WWF into a global entertainment phenomenon.</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_Cena">He holds the record for the most Make-A-Wish Foundation wishes granted of any individual, fulfilling over 650 wishes, while also transitioning into a successful Hollywood acting career.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Stone_Cold_Steve_Austin">His beer-smashing, authority-defying &apos;Stone Cold&apos; character in the late 1990s became the defining anti-hero of wrestling&apos;s Attitude Era and helped WWE win the Monday Night Wars.</hint>
  <hint wiki="MrBeast">He built YouTube&apos;s most-subscribed individual channel through increasingly elaborate stunts and giveaways, including recreating the entire Squid Game set and giving away millions of dollars.</hint>
  <hint wiki="PewDiePie">The Swedish gaming commentator was YouTube&apos;s most-subscribed individual creator for years, sparking a cultural moment when T-Series challenged his crown in a months-long subscriber race.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Logan_Paul">After a major controversy over a video filmed in Japan&apos;s Aokigahara forest, he rebranded by boxing Floyd Mayweather in an exhibition match and co-founding the Prime energy drink brand.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jake_Paul">He parlayed his YouTube fame into a professional boxing career, defeating several former MMA champions and eventually fighting Mike Tyson in a Netflix-streamed event.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Markiplier">Known for his hugely popular horror game playthroughs, he raised millions for charity through livestreams and later co-directed an interactive YouTube film with a branching choose-your-own-adventure format.</hint>
  <hint wiki="KSI_(entertainer)">The British YouTuber turned his rivalry with Logan Paul into two boxing matches that drew millions of pay-per-view buys and helped legitimize the YouTube-to-boxing pipeline.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Charli_D&apos;Amelio">She became TikTok&apos;s most-followed creator as a teenager almost purely through dance videos, reaching 100 million followers faster than anyone else on the platform.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Addison_Rae">One of TikTok&apos;s earliest mega-stars, she leveraged her following into a Netflix film deal and a music career, becoming one of the highest-earning TikTok creators.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Khaby_Lame">The Senegalese-Italian creator became the most-followed person on TikTok without ever speaking, using deadpan reactions to mock needlessly complicated life-hack videos.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bella_Poarch">Her slow head-bob lip-sync to &apos;M to the B&apos; became the most-liked video in TikTok history at the time, catapulting her to fame before she pivoted to a music career.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ninja_(gamer)">He became the face of competitive Fortnite streaming, was the first gamer on the cover of ESPN Magazine, and once drew 635,000 concurrent viewers for a single stream with Drake.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pokimane">One of Twitch&apos;s most-watched female streamers, she co-founded the Offline TV content house and became a symbol of the mainstream crossover of gaming culture.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dr_Disrespect">Known for his theatrical villain persona complete with mullet wig and wraparound shades, he was mysteriously and permanently banned from Twitch in 2020 with no official explanation ever given.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kai_Cenat">He broke the record for most concurrent Twitch subscribers multiple times and became famous for marathon &apos;subathon&apos; streams lasting weeks, cementing his status as the platform&apos;s biggest star.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hasan_Piker">The nephew of The Young Turks founder Cenk Uygur, he became Twitch&apos;s most-watched political streamer by blending leftist commentary with gaming and pop culture.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Joe_Rogan">His long-form podcast became the world&apos;s most-listened-to podcast, drawing controversy when he signed an exclusive $200 million deal with Spotify and platformed guests with fringe views.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lex_Fridman">The MIT researcher turned podcaster is known for marathon multi-hour interviews with scientists, world leaders, and tech figures, as well as his signature black suit worn in every episode.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Andrew_Tate">The former kickboxing world champion became one of the most-searched people on the internet in 2022 through viral misogynistic content, before being banned from major platforms and arrested in Romania.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jordan_Peterson">His 12 Rules for Life sold millions of copies worldwide, and a viral 2018 Channel 4 interview in which he sparred with journalist Cathy Newman became one of the most-watched political interviews on YouTube.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ellen_DeGeneres">She came out as gay in a 1997 episode of her sitcom in a landmark TV moment, later building a daytime talk show empire that ran for 19 seasons before ending amid workplace culture allegations.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jimmy_Fallon">Host of The Tonight Show known for his celebrity games and musical impressions, he became famous for making his guests laugh during SNL sketches, often inadvertently.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jimmy_Kimmel">The host of Jimmy Kimmel Live is known for his annual &apos;I Told My Kids I Ate Their Halloween Candy&apos; viral segments and his emotional monologues on healthcare and gun control.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Stephen_Colbert">He spent nine years playing an exaggerated right-wing pundit on The Colbert Report before dropping the character to take over The Late Show, where his Trump-era monologues went massively viral.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Conan_O&apos;Brien">After a very public falling-out with NBC over The Tonight Show that became a national story, he reinvented late night by leaning into self-deprecating absurdism and eventually launched a hit travel podcast.</hint>
  <hint wiki="David_Letterman">The host of Late Night and then the Late Show for over 30 years, he pioneered the modern talk show format and is famous for his gap-toothed wit and the Top Ten List.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jay_Leno">He hosted The Tonight Show for 22 years and is as famous for his passion for collecting hundreds of vintage cars and motorcycles as he is for his massive chin.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Johnny_Carson">He defined late-night television for 30 years as host of The Tonight Show, and his endorsement of a little-known stand-up on air was considered a career-making moment for comedians.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jon_Stewart">His satirical Daily Show became the primary source of news for millions of young Americans and is credited with influencing real political coverage during the Bush and Obama eras.</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_Oliver">His long-form investigative comedy segments on Last Week Tonight have repeatedly caused real-world consequences, including crashing the FCC&apos;s website during his net neutrality piece.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Trevor_Noah">The South African comedian took over The Daily Show from Jon Stewart and wrote a bestselling memoir, Born a Crime, about growing up mixed-race under apartheid.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Larry_King">He conducted over 50,000 interviews across his career, wearing his signature suspenders every night on CNN&apos;s Larry King Live for 25 years.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Barbara_Walters">She was the first female co-anchor of a network evening news program and created The View, a daytime panel show that became a cultural institution for political and social debate.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Anderson_Cooper">The silver-haired CNN anchor is the son of Gloria Vanderbilt and became a household name for his on-the-ground hurricane and war coverage, including his emotional reporting from post-Katrina New Orleans.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Walter_Cronkite">Known as &apos;the most trusted man in America,&apos; his on-air emotional reaction to JFK&apos;s assassination and his editorial declaring the Vietnam War a stalemate helped shape public opinion.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Diane_Sawyer">A former Nixon White House aide turned award-winning journalist, she conducted some of television&apos;s most-watched interviews, including a 2015 sit-down with Caitlyn Jenner.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Katie_Couric">She became the first female solo anchor of a major U.S. network evening news broadcast when she joined CBS News in 2006, after 15 years as a beloved Today show host.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tucker_Carlson">The bow-tie-wearing host became Fox News&apos;s most-watched primetime anchor before being abruptly fired in 2023, then relaunching independently on X (formerly Twitter).</hint>
  <hint wiki="Rachel_Maddow">Her MSNBC show became cable news&apos;s top-rated program, known for its long narrative-style cold opens that connected historical dots to current political events.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Phil_McGraw">Phil McGraw built a daytime TV empire dispensing tough-love advice after being discovered by Oprah Winfrey, but became controversial for his handling of mentally vulnerable guests.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Mehmet_Oz">The celebrity heart surgeon became a daytime TV health guru through Oprah&apos;s endorsement, later running for U.S. Senate in Pennsylvania where his promotion of miracle cures became a major liability.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Judy_Sheindlin">Judge Judy Sheindlin&apos;s no-nonsense courtroom show became the longest-running court program in TV history, and she negotiated a salary that made her the highest-paid TV personality for years.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ryan_Seacrest">The seemingly omnipresent host ran American Idol and E! News simultaneously while also doing morning radio, building a multi-platform media empire before eventually taking over from Pat Sajak on Wheel of Fortune.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Simon_Cowell">The notoriously blunt music executive and TV judge created and produced American Idol, The X Factor, and Britain&apos;s Got Talent, launching the careers of artists including One Direction and Susan Boyle.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Howard_Stern">The self-proclaimed &apos;King of All Media&apos; pushed the boundaries of broadcast radio for decades, earning record FCC fines, before moving to SiriusXM satellite radio in a $500 million deal.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bob_Ross">The soft-spoken painter with the iconic afro taught millions to paint &apos;happy little trees&apos; on his PBS show The Joy of Painting, filming over 400 episodes in 11 years and becoming a posthumous internet icon.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Fred_Rogers">Fred Rogers testified before the U.S. Senate in 1969 in a quiet, sincere speech that convinced lawmakers to preserve $20 million in PBS funding, famously reciting the lyrics to &apos;What Do You Do with the Mad That You Feel.&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Steve_Irwin">The exuberant Australian &apos;Crocodile Hunter&apos; brought wildlife conservation to millions through his fearless hands-on encounters with dangerous animals, before dying tragically from a stingray barb in 2006.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Anthony_Bourdain">The former New York chef turned the travel food show into literary television with Parts Unknown, earning Peabody Awards for episodes that used food as a lens into geopolitics and human stories.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jerry_Seinfeld">He co-created and starred in Seinfeld, often called the greatest sitcom ever made, built around observational comedy about nothing, and famously turned down $5 million per episode to end the show on his own terms.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Chris_Rock">His 1996 special Bring the Pain is considered one of the greatest stand-up specials ever recorded, and his commentary on race in America made him one of comedy&apos;s sharpest social critics.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dave_Chappelle">He famously walked away from a $50 million Comedy Central deal in 2005 at the height of Chappelle&apos;s Show&apos;s popularity, later returning with Netflix specials that reignited fierce cultural debate.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kevin_Hart">He sold out Madison Square Garden multiple times and became one of Hollywood&apos;s highest-paid actors, building a comedy-to-film crossover career rivaled by few stand-ups in history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Eddie_Izzard">The British comedian pioneered a freewheeling, history-obsessed rambling style, often performing in heels and makeup, including a famous hour-long bit about the British Empire and Darth Vader&apos;s cafeteria.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ricky_Gervais">He created the original British version of The Office, widely considered one of the greatest sitcoms ever made, and became known for his fearlessly provocative Golden Globes hosting appearances.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sarah_Silverman">Her deliberately offensive and taboo-breaking comedy style made her one of the most polarizing voices in stand-up, and her 2005 mockumentary Jesus Is Magic blended music and comedy in an unusual format.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Amy_Schumer">Her sketch series Inside Amy Schumer won a Peabody Award and she became one of comedy&apos;s biggest names after her film Trainwreck, co-written with Judd Apatow, was a surprise box-office hit.</hint>
  <hint wiki="George_Carlin">His &apos;Seven Words You Can Never Say on Television&apos; routine led to a landmark 1978 Supreme Court case that defined the FCC&apos;s power to regulate broadcast content.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Richard_Pryor">His brutally autobiographical comedy about race, addiction, and his own near-fatal self-immolation set the template for confessional stand-up and influenced virtually every comedian who followed him.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bill_Cosby">His clean family-friendly comedy made him one of America&apos;s most beloved entertainers for decades, before he was convicted of sexual assault in 2018 following accusations from dozens of women.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Joan_Rivers">The acid-tongued comedian broke glass ceilings as one of the first women to host a late-night talk show and reinvented herself multiple times, becoming famous for her red-carpet fashion commentary.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bob_Hope">He entertained U.S. troops overseas for nearly 50 years from World War II through the Gulf War, and his 14 Academy Awards hosting stints remain a record.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Rodney_Dangerfield">His &apos;I don&apos;t get no respect&apos; catchphrase and bulging-eyed delivery made him a comedy icon, but he didn&apos;t achieve mainstream fame until his mid-40s, making his comeback one of comedy&apos;s great late-bloomer stories.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bo_Burnham">He started as a teenage YouTube comedian and evolved into a writer-director whose Netflix special Inside, filmed entirely alone during COVID-19 lockdown, won three Emmy Awards.</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_Mulaney">His meticulous, storytelling-heavy stand-up style drew comparisons to classic comedians, but his personal life became tabloid fodder when he entered rehab and left his wife in a very public 2021 spiral.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pete_Davidson">The Saturday Night Live cast member became as famous for his high-profile celebrity relationships, including a brief engagement to Ariana Grande, as for his self-deprecating tattoo-covered persona.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Naomi_Campbell">One of the original supermodels and the first Black woman on the cover of French Vogue, she was also notorious for a series of phone-throwing incidents involving her personal assistants.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Cindy_Crawford">Her iconic mole and athletic physique made her one of the defining supermodels of the late 1980s and 1990s, and she appeared on over 500 magazine covers during her career.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tyra_Banks">She was the first Black woman to appear on the covers of the Sports Illustrated Swimsuit Issue and the Victoria&apos;s Secret catalog, later creating and hosting America&apos;s Next Top Model.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Heidi_Klum">The German supermodel became a cultural fixture as the longtime host and producer of Project Runway and as a Victoria&apos;s Secret Angel, famous for her elaborate and theatrical Halloween costumes.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kate_Moss">Her waif-like look in the early 1990s defined a controversial shift in fashion aesthetics and she famously appeared in Calvin Klein campaigns that became some of the most talked-about ads of the decade.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Gisele_Bündchen">At her peak she was the world&apos;s highest-paid model for 15 consecutive years and walked the final Victoria&apos;s Secret Fashion Show in 2018 in one of fashion&apos;s most celebrated farewell moments.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bella_Hadid">Named &apos;Model of the Year&apos; by industry bible Models.com multiple times, she wore the iconic spray-painted &apos;naked dress&apos; at the 2016 Cannes Film Festival in one of fashion&apos;s most viral moments.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Gigi_Hadid">She became one of the most in-demand runway models of her generation while maintaining a massive social media presence, and walked in a record number of shows during a single Fashion Week season.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kendall_Jenner">Transitioning from Keeping Up with the Kardashians to the highest-paid model in the world by 2018, she became the face of dozens of luxury brands, but a Pepsi ad appearance sparked one of the decade&apos;s biggest advertising controversies.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Karlie_Kloss">One of the most recognizable runway models of the 2010s, she leveraged her career into tech philanthropy by founding Kode with Klossy, a coding camp for young women.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ralph_Lauren">Born Ralph Lifshitz in the Bronx, he built a global empire from a line of wide neckties and turned the polo shirt into an American status symbol, without ever having formally studied fashion design.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Calvin_Klein">His minimalist aesthetic and provocative advertising, featuring a 15-year-old Brooke Shields saying &apos;nothing comes between me and my Calvins&apos;: made him as famous for controversy as for design.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tommy_Hilfiger">He turned preppy American sportswear into a global brand by being one of the first designers to embrace hip-hop culture in the 1990s, a crossover that transformed the brand&apos;s identity.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Donatella_Versace">She took over her brother Gianni&apos;s fashion house after his murder in 1997 and maintained its maximalist, rock-star glamour identity, becoming as recognizable a figure as the brand itself.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Gianni_Versace">The Italian designer who made fashion theatrical and sexy was murdered outside his Miami mansion in 1997 by serial killer Andrew Cunanan, in one of fashion&apos;s most shocking tragedies.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Giorgio_Armani">He dressed Richard Gere in American Gigolo in 1980 and is credited almost single-handedly with changing how men dressed in suits, removing the structure and making tailoring soft and unlined.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Karl_Lagerfeld">The ponytailed, fan-carrying creative director of Chanel for over 35 years, he also simultaneously helmed Fendi and his own label while producing a legendary volume of sketches and opinions.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Yves_Saint_Laurent_(designer)">He is credited with inventing the modern women&apos;s power suit, the Le Smoking tuxedo, in 1966, a garment so radical that a woman was once turned away from a Paris restaurant for wearing it.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Marc_Jacobs">He was fired from Perry Ellis after his 1993 &apos;grunge collection&apos; was deemed a commercial disaster, only for that same collection to later be recognized as one of the most influential in American fashion history.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tom_Ford">He revived Gucci from near-bankruptcy in the 1990s with overtly sexual, glamorous designs, then built his own namesake brand spanning fashion, beauty, and eventually film directing.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Vera_Wang">A figure skater who failed to make the 1968 U.S. Olympic team, she pivoted to fashion and transformed the bridal industry in her 40s, becoming the definitive name in high-end wedding gowns.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Anna_Wintour">The icy, bob-haired editor-in-chief of Vogue has wielded more power over the fashion industry than perhaps any other individual for four decades, and inspired the character Miranda Priestly in The Devil Wears Prada.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kim_Kardashian">A 2007 sex tape leak became the unlikely launchpad for a media empire spanning reality TV, a billion-dollar shapewear brand (SKIMS), and a serious push toward criminal justice reform advocacy.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kourtney_Kardashian">The eldest Kardashian sister launched the lifestyle brand Poosh and made headlines when her lavish wedding to drummer Travis Barker in Italy became one of the most-covered celebrity events of 2022.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Khloé_Kardashian">She built a fitness-focused brand and starred in Revenge Body after her very public relationship troubles played out on television, becoming the Kardashian most associated with personal reinvention.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kris_Jenner">The self-described &apos;momager&apos; orchestrated the rise of the entire Kardashian-Jenner media empire, negotiating deals and producing Keeping Up with the Kardashians for 20 seasons.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kylie_Jenner">She built Kylie Cosmetics largely through Instagram and Snapchat into a brand Forbes initially valued at nearly $1 billion, making her one of the youngest self-made billionaires, a label that later sparked significant controversy.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Caitlyn_Jenner">Won the 1976 Olympic decathlon as Bruce Jenner, widely celebrated as the world&apos;s greatest athlete, before later becoming a prominent transgender public figure.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Paris_Hilton">Her leaked 2003 home video and the reality show &apos;The Simple Life&apos; made her one of the first modern celebrities famous largely for being famous.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Gordon_Ramsay">Holds three Michelin stars at his London restaurant and became a global TV phenomenon by screaming at amateur cooks on &apos;Hell&apos;s Kitchen&apos; and &apos;MasterChef&apos;.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Julia_Child">A former OSS spy who didn&apos;t learn to cook until her 30s, she brought French cuisine to American kitchens through her landmark 1961 book &apos;Mastering the Art of French Cooking&apos;.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Wolfgang_Puck">Revolutionized upscale American dining in the 1980s with smoked-salmon pizza at Spago, and has catered the Governors Ball after the Oscars for decades.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jamie_Oliver">A British chef who launched a real-world campaign to overhaul school lunch menus in the UK and US, taking on governments over children&apos;s nutrition.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bobby_Flay">Built his empire around bold Southwestern flavors and became famous for staging surprise &apos;throwdowns&apos; against hometown cooks on his Food Network show.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Rachael_Ray">Popularized the concept of the &apos;30-Minute Meal&apos; and built a media empire from a simple cooking segment, never having attended culinary school.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Guy_Fieri">Bleached spiky hair, backward sunglasses, and a &apos;67 Camaro are his trademarks as the self-styled &apos;Mayor of Flavortown&apos; on &apos;Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives&apos;.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Salt_Bae">Turkish butcher Nusret Gökçe became a global meme in 2017 for his theatrical slow-motion salt sprinkle over a perfectly rested steak.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Stephen_King">Has published over 60 horror novels under his own name and the pseudonym Richard Bachman, with works like &apos;The Shining&apos; and &apos;It&apos; defining modern horror.</hint>
  <hint wiki="J._K._Rowling">A single mother on welfare, she wrote the first Harry Potter novel in Edinburgh cafés and went on to sell over 500 million books worldwide.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Maya_Angelou">Her 1969 memoir &apos;I Know Why the Caged Bird Sings&apos; was one of the first autobiographies by a Black American woman to reach a mainstream audience, and she recited a poem at Bill Clinton&apos;s inauguration.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Toni_Morrison">The first African American woman to win the Nobel Prize in Literature, known for &apos;Beloved&apos;, a ghost story rooted in the brutal reality of American slavery.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Margaret_Atwood">A Canadian writer whose 1985 dystopian novel &apos;The Handmaid&apos;s Tale&apos; surged back onto bestseller lists and spawned a hit TV series after the 2016 US election.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Salman_Rushdie">His 1988 novel &apos;The Satanic Verses&apos; led Iran&apos;s Ayatollah Khomeini to issue a fatwa calling for his death, forcing him into hiding for nearly a decade.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Neil_Gaiman">Blends mythology, folklore, and fantasy in works like &apos;American Gods&apos; and &apos;Sandman&apos;, the groundbreaking DC Comics series that helped legitimize graphic novels as literature.</hint>
  <hint wiki="George_R._R._Martin">Created the brutal, sprawling fantasy world of Westeros in &apos;A Song of Ice and Fire&apos;, inspiring &apos;Game of Thrones&apos; and making fans wait decades for the next book.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dan_Brown">&apos;The Da Vinci Code&apos; sparked worldwide controversy in 2003 by weaving conspiracy theories about the Catholic Church and the Holy Grail into a thriller that sold 80 million copies.</hint>
  <hint wiki="James_Patterson">Has had more New York Times #1 bestsellers than any other author in history and reportedly sells roughly one book every 23 minutes around the world.</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_Grisham">A former Mississippi defense attorney who wrote his first legal thriller &apos;A Time to Kill&apos; before dawn each morning and went on to define the legal thriller genre.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Malcolm_Gladwell">Popularized ideas like the &apos;10,000-hour rule&apos; and the &apos;tipping point&apos; in accessible, anecdote-driven books that made social science feel like a page-turner.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Roald_Dahl">A WWII RAF fighter pilot and spy turned beloved children&apos;s author, whose dark, subversive stories like &apos;Charlie and the Chocolate Factory&apos; also hide a very adult edge.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Dr._Seuss">Theodor Geisel wrote &apos;The Cat in the Hat&apos; using a deliberately limited vocabulary of 236 words, on a bet that he couldn&apos;t write an engaging children&apos;s book with so few.</hint>
  <hint wiki="C._S._Lewis">A lifelong atheist who converted to Christianity after late-night walks with J.R.R. Tolkien, and hid a complete Christian allegory inside the &apos;Chronicles of Narnia&apos;.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Harper_Lee">Published only one novel in her lifetime, &apos;To Kill a Mockingbird&apos;, which won the Pulitzer Prize in 1961 and became one of the most assigned books in American schools.</hint>
  <hint wiki="F._Scott_Fitzgerald">The gilded parties, bootleg champagne, and doomed romance of 1920s Long Island he captured in &apos;The Great Gatsby&apos; were drawn largely from his own turbulent life.</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_Steinbeck">His Depression-era novel &apos;The Grapes of Wrath&apos; about Dust Bowl migrants was so politically explosive that it was burned in several California counties.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ray_Bradbury">&apos;Fahrenheit 451&apos;, his 1953 novel about book-burning, was itself ironically censored in some school editions: passages about religion and alcohol were quietly removed.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Isaac_Asimov">Wrote or edited over 500 books spanning almost every major category in the Dewey Decimal System, and his &apos;Three Laws of Robotics&apos; shaped how science fiction, and real AI ethics, thinks about machines.</hint>
  <hint wiki="H._G._Wells">His 1898 novel &apos;The War of the Worlds&apos; was so convincingly adapted as a 1938 radio broadcast by Orson Welles that it allegedly caused widespread panic across the US.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jules_Verne">His 19th-century adventure novels predicted the submarine, the moon rocket, and videoconferencing with uncanny accuracy, earning him the title &apos;Father of Science Fiction&apos;.</hint>
  <hint wiki="J._D._Salinger">Published &apos;The Catcher in the Rye&apos; in 1951 and then retreated into total seclusion in rural New Hampshire, refusing interviews and publishing nothing more for decades.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Kurt_Vonnegut">A survivor of the Allied firebombing of Dresden, sheltering in a slaughterhouse, he turned that trauma into &apos;Slaughterhouse-Five&apos;, one of the great antiwar novels.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Truman_Capote">His 1966 &apos;Black and White Ball&apos; at the Plaza Hotel was dubbed the &apos;Party of the Century&apos;, but his unfinished novel &apos;Answered Prayers&apos; destroyed his high-society friendships forever.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hunter_S._Thompson">Invented &apos;Gonzo journalism&apos; by embedding himself so deeply in stories, riding with the Hells Angels, covering Nixon&apos;s 1972 campaign, that he became the story.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Aldous_Huxley">Wrote &apos;Brave New World&apos; in just four months in 1931; he and George Orwell both died on the same day, November 22, 1963, overshadowed by JFK&apos;s assassination.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sylvia_Plath">Her semi-autobiographical novel &apos;The Bell Jar&apos; and her raw, confessional poetry redefined how personal anguish could be turned into literary art before her death at 30.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Andy_Warhol">Turned a Campbell&apos;s Soup can and Marilyn Monroe&apos;s face into high art, and his New York studio &apos;The Factory&apos; became the epicenter of 1960s pop culture.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jackson_Pollock">Pioneered &apos;action painting&apos; by laying canvas on the floor and dripping, flinging, and pouring paint, a method Life magazine celebrated by asking &apos;Is he the greatest living painter in the US?&apos;</hint>
  <hint wiki="Georgia_O&apos;Keeffe">Spent decades painting the bleached skulls and vast desert landscapes of New Mexico, becoming the &apos;Mother of American Modernism&apos; while largely shunning the New York art world.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Norman_Rockwell">Spent 47 years illustrating the cover of the Saturday Evening Post, creating an idealized portrait of American small-town life that became inseparable from US nostalgia.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Banksy">An anonymous British street artist whose satirical stencils appear overnight on walls from London to Gaza, and whose painting famously shredded itself moments after selling at auction for £1 million.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jean-Michel_Basquiat">Rose from a New York graffiti writer tagging under the name &apos;SAMO©&apos; to sell paintings for millions before dying of a heroin overdose at just 27.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Roy_Lichtenstein">Borrowed the bold outlines, Ben-Day dots, and melodrama of comic strips to create monumental fine-art paintings that blurred the line between popular culture and high art.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Henri_Matisse">After illness confined him to a wheelchair in his 70s, he invented an entirely new medium, cutting and arranging painted paper, producing some of his most celebrated works.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Claude_Monet">Painted his famous water lily series while nearly blind from cataracts, and created an outdoor studio pond at Giverny that he tended as obsessively as a canvas.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pierre-Auguste_Renoir">Continued painting almost until his death despite crippling arthritis that left him unable to hold a brush, reportedly having it tied to his hand.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Edgar_Degas">Obsessively painted and sculpted ballet dancers, producing over 600 works on the subject, despite never romanticizing the art form, showing the grueling labor behind the grace.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Paul_Cézanne">Worked in near isolation in Provence for decades, but his geometric approach to apples, mountains, and card players directly inspired Picasso and became the bridge to Cubism.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Edvard_Munch">His 1893 painting &apos;The Scream&apos;, inspired by a real moment of existential dread on a walk, has become one of the most recognizable images of modern anxiety.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Gustav_Klimt">His golden, ornate portrait &apos;Woman in Gold&apos; was looted by Nazis and became the subject of a landmark legal battle won by the subject&apos;s niece over 60 years later.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Marcel_Duchamp">Submitted a factory-bought urinal titled &apos;Fountain&apos; to an art exhibition in 1917, asking whether context alone makes something art, a question the art world still hasn&apos;t settled.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Yayoi_Kusama">A Japanese artist who has voluntarily lived in a psychiatric institution since 1977, continuing to create from there; her mirrored &apos;Infinity Rooms&apos; now draw hours-long queues worldwide.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ansel_Adams">His sweeping black-and-white photographs of Yosemite and the American West, often made on large-format cameras on treacherous terrain, helped secure the expansion of the national park system.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Annie_Leibovitz">Her Rolling Stone cover images, including the last photo of John Lennon hours before his murder, and her intimate Vanity Fair celebrity portraits defined decades of American pop culture photography.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ferdinand_Magellan">Led the first expedition to circumnavigate the globe, though he was killed in the Philippines before completing the voyage, and only 18 of his original 270 crew members made it home.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Lewis_and_Clark_Expedition">Led the Corps of Discovery 8,000 miles across unmapped North America to the Pacific Ocean between 1804 and 1806, guided in large part by a teenage Shoshone woman.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Roald_Amundsen">Beat Robert Falcon Scott to the South Pole in December 1911 by using sled dogs efficiently and preparing obsessively, while Scott&apos;s rival British team perished on the return journey.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ernest_Shackleton">When his ship &apos;Endurance&apos; was crushed by Antarctic ice, he led all 27 of his crew to safety across hundreds of miles of open ocean in a lifeboat, losing not a single man.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Edmund_Hillary">On May 29, 1953, the New Zealand beekeeper became one of the first two confirmed humans to summit Everest; he learned of his knighthood while still on the mountain.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tenzing_Norgay">The Sherpa mountaineer who summited Everest alongside Edmund Hillary declined to say who stepped onto the top first, calling it a private moment shared between friends.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jacques_Cousteau">Co-invented the Aqua-Lung scuba device in 1943 and spent decades aboard his ship Calypso filming the underwater world, bringing the ocean into living rooms worldwide.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Evel_Knievel">His failed 1974 attempt to rocket across Snake River Canyon attracted more live TV viewers than the moon landing, despite ending in an inglorious splashdown.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Felix_Baumgartner">In 2012 he skydived from a capsule 24 miles above Earth, breaking the sound barrier in freefall and setting multiple world records before landing safely in the New Mexico desert.</hint>
  <hint wiki="George_S._Patton">Commanded the fastest armored advance in military history across France in 1944, and controversially slapped a shell-shocked soldier in a military hospital, nearly ending his career.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Douglas_MacArthur">Famously pledged &apos;I shall return&apos; when forced out of the Philippines in 1942, waded ashore to fulfill the promise in 1944, and later accepted Japan&apos;s formal surrender on the USS Missouri.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Robert_E._Lee">Turned down command of the Union Army to instead lead the Confederate Army of Northern Virginia, believing his loyalty to Virginia outweighed his duty to the United States.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Stonewall_Jackson">Earned his nickname by standing firm &apos;like a stone wall&apos; at the First Battle of Bull Run; he was accidentally shot by his own troops at Chancellorsville and died days later.</hint>
  <hint wiki="William_Tecumseh_Sherman">His &apos;March to the Sea&apos; through Georgia in 1864 deliberately destroyed civilian infrastructure to break the South&apos;s will to fight, pioneering the concept of total war.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Erwin_Rommel">So respected by both sides in North Africa that Churchill praised him in Parliament, and so feared that Allied commanders pinned his portrait on their walls as a motivational reminder.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Al_Capone">Ran Chicago&apos;s criminal empire during Prohibition but was ultimately brought down not by violence charges, but by a federal tax evasion conviction in 1931.</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_Gotti">Known as the &apos;Teflon Don&apos; after three high-profile acquittals, he was finally convicted in 1992 largely because his underboss Sammy &apos;The Bull&apos; Gravano turned government witness.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pablo_Escobar">At his peak the Colombian cocaine kingpin was smuggling 15 tons of cocaine into the US per day and reportedly spending $2,500 a month just on rubber bands for his cash.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Bonnie_and_Clyde">The Depression-era outlaw couple robbed banks and small stores across five states, becoming folk anti-heroes before being ambushed in a hail of 130 bullets on a Louisiana road in 1934.</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_Dillinger">Escaped from an &apos;escape-proof&apos; Indiana jail using a wooden gun he&apos;d whittled himself, before being betrayed by the &apos;Lady in Red&apos; and shot outside a Chicago theater in 1934.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jesse_James">A former Confederate guerrilla who became America&apos;s most romanticized outlaw, he was shot in the back of the head by a fellow gang member hoping to collect a reward.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Billy_the_Kid">The New Mexico outlaw reportedly killed 21 men by his 21st birthday, historians put the real number closer to 8, and was shot dead by Sheriff Pat Garrett in a darkened room.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ted_Bundy">Charming and articulate enough to act as his own attorney, he confessed to 30 murders across seven states shortly before his 1989 execution, to the end fascinated by his own case.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Charles_Manson">Never personally committed the 1969 Tate-LaBianca murders himself but orchestrated them through his &apos;Family&apos; cult, believing the killings would trigger a race war he called &apos;Helter Skelter&apos;.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jeffrey_Dahmer">A Milwaukee factory worker who murdered and dismembered 17 men and boys between 1978 and 1991; one victim escaped and led police to the apartment where his crimes were finally uncovered.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Confucius">A wandering Chinese scholar who spent 13 years traveling from court to court trying unsuccessfully to get rulers to adopt his ideas; his teachings became the foundation of Chinese society only after his death.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sun_Tzu">The ancient Chinese general&apos;s &apos;The Art of War&apos;, written around 500 BC, is still required reading at military academies and business schools worldwide.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Gautama_Buddha">Born a sheltered Hindu prince in Nepal, Siddhartha Gautama abandoned his palace and family at 29 to seek enlightenment, and attained it meditating beneath a fig tree.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jesus">A carpenter&apos;s son from Galilee whose three-year public ministry, death by crucifixion, and reported resurrection became the founding events of the world&apos;s largest religion.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Muhammad">The Prophet of Islam received the first Quranic revelations at age 40 in a cave outside Mecca, and within 23 years had united the warring tribes of Arabia under a new faith.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Moses">According to the Bible, he parted the Red Sea to lead the Israelites out of Egyptian slavery, received the Ten Commandments on Mount Sinai, and yet never entered the Promised Land himself.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Socrates">Never wrote anything down; everything we know about him comes through his students, and his method of relentless questioning so irritated Athens that he was tried and forced to drink hemlock.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Charlemagne">United most of Western Europe for the first time since Rome, was crowned Holy Roman Emperor on Christmas Day 800 AD, and is considered the founding father of both France and Germany.</hint>
  <hint wiki="King_Arthur">The legendary British king whose court at Camelot, the Knights of the Round Table, and the quest for the Holy Grail have inspired literature and film for over a thousand years.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Vlad_the_Impaler">The 15th-century Wallachian prince who impaled tens of thousands of enemies on stakes was likely the historical inspiration for Bram Stoker&apos;s Count Dracula.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Henry_VIII">Broke with the Catholic Church and established the Church of England primarily so he could divorce his first wife, eventually having six wives in total: two of whom he beheaded.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Louis_XIV">Ruled France for 72 years, the longest reign of any major European monarch, and reportedly declared &apos;L&apos;état, c&apos;est moi&apos; (&apos;I am the state&apos;), centralizing all power in himself.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Tutankhamun">The boy pharaoh died at around 19 and was largely forgotten for 3,000 years until Howard Carter opened his nearly intact tomb in 1922, triggering a worldwide obsession with ancient Egypt.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ramesses_II">Ruled Egypt for 66 years, built more monuments and fathered more children (over 100) than any other pharaoh, and had his name carved so deeply into existing temples that successors couldn&apos;t erase it.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Nefertiti">The Egyptian queen whose 1912 limestone bust is one of the most copied artworks of antiquity; she may have briefly ruled Egypt as pharaoh in her own right after Akhenaten&apos;s death.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hammurabi">The Babylonian king who inscribed one of the world&apos;s first written legal codes on a seven-foot stone column around 1754 BC, including the famous &apos;eye for an eye&apos; principle.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Hernán_Cortés">With just 500 men, horses, and steel weapons, he toppled the Aztec Empire: aided decisively by smallpox and by alliances with peoples who resented Aztec rule.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Francisco_Pizarro">An illiterate Spanish pig farmer who led the conquest of the Inca Empire, capturing Emperor Atahualpa in 1532 and demanding a ransom of gold that filled an entire room.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Davy_Crockett">A Tennessee frontiersman and congressman who became a legend through his own tall tales, dying at the Alamo in 1836 and becoming the most mythologized figure of the American frontier.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Daniel_Boone">Blazed the Wilderness Road through the Cumberland Gap, founding Boonesborough in Kentucky, and was captured twice by Shawnee warriors: one time being adopted into the tribe.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sitting_Bull">The Hunkpapa Lakota chief who united the Sioux and Cheyenne nations at the Battle of Little Bighorn in 1876, where they annihilated Custer&apos;s Seventh Cavalry.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Crazy_Horse">Never allowed his photograph to be taken and refused to live on a reservation; killed in a disputed incident at a US Army fort in 1877, he is now the subject of the world&apos;s largest mountain sculpture.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Geronimo">The Apache leader who outmaneuvered thousands of US and Mexican troops for decades before surrendering in 1886; his name became a battle cry for American paratroopers in WWII.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Pocahontas">The Powhatan chief&apos;s daughter who helped broker an uneasy peace between her people and Jamestown&apos;s English settlers, was later captured, converted to Christianity, and died in England aged around 21.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Sacagawea">The Shoshone teenager who joined the Lewis and Clark expedition as an interpreter while carrying a newborn, and whose presence signaled to other tribes that the expedition was peaceful.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Helen_Keller">Left deaf and blind by illness at 19 months, she learned to read, write, and speak through the extraordinary teaching of Anne Sullivan, and went on to become a published author and political activist.</hint>
  <hint wiki="John_Wayne">The quintessential Hollywood cowboy who starred in over 170 films, won an Oscar for &apos;True Grit&apos;, and became such a symbol of American masculinity that the US Congress awarded him the Congressional Gold Medal.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Gene_Kelly">Choreographed and performed the legendary &apos;Singin&apos; in the Rain&apos; sequence in one take while running a high fever, redefining what dance could look like on film.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Fred_Astaire">His partnership with Ginger Rogers in 1930s Hollywood musicals was so perfectly matched that it was said she did everything he did but backwards and in high heels.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ginger_Rogers">Won the Academy Award for Best Actress for &apos;Kitty Foyle&apos;, a dramatic role, proving she was far more than Fred Astaire&apos;s dancing partner, though their ten films together remain iconic.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Jane_Fonda">Won two Oscars for acting, launched a fitness video empire in the 1980s, and earned the lasting nickname &apos;Hanoi Jane&apos; for a controversial visit to North Vietnam during the war.</hint>
  <hint wiki="The_Undertaker">The WWE&apos;s legendary &apos;Dead Man&apos; character, played by Mark Calaway, went undefeated at WrestleMania for 21 years, a streak so iconic that its ending in 2014 left fans visibly in shock.</hint>
  <hint wiki="André_the_Giant">Stood 7&apos;4&quot; and weighed over 500 pounds, went undefeated in wrestling for 15 years, could reportedly drink 100 beers in a single sitting, and was immortalized in the &apos;OBEY&apos; street art poster.</hint>
  <hint wiki="Ric_Flair">&apos;To be the man, you gotta beat the man&apos;: the &apos;Nature Boy&apos; won a record 16 world heavyweight championships and his sequined robes, &apos;WOO!&apos; catchphrase, and figure-four leglock defined professional wrestling for four decades.</hint>
</hints>